<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="http://noahtheduke.github.io/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Thoughts and bits</title><link>http://noahtheduke.github.io/</link><description>This blog is awesome</description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 22:40:41 -0400</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-27-archibus-n1-tutorial/</guid><link>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-27-archibus-n1-tutorial/</link><title>Archibus and the SELECT N+1 Problem</title><description>IntroThis past week, I had the opportunity to contribute to an existing custom report built for a client.
It loaded incredibly slowly, so in between working on the contribution I had been tasked with, I also took it upon myself to speed it up.
I think it’s time to share what I’ve learned.CaveatA big problem is that some portions of Archibus’ Web Central are poorly documented, so understanding exactly how a given feature works in detail can be time-consuming and even with effort subtleties can be missed.
 Don’t just take my word for how any given element works or doesn’t work.That being said, I’m here to help you make certain parts of your Archibus app run fast and beautiful, and blow away everyone who uses them.</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-08-blank/</guid><link>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-08-blank/</link><title>Blank</title><description>I’m siting here at 1215 after another long day, and I’ve been thinking to myself, what am I doing? I don’t need to spend the money, I don’t need to drink wine, I don’t need any of this.
On the other hand, the wine tastes amazing, the music in my headphones and the music played by the two jazz dudes in the corner are both bangin, I’m written some really good facebook posts today.
I don’t regret my decisions.I had dinner with dad, and he whipped out some classic Jon Bogart-isms.
Stuff like, if I actually wanted to do certain things I’d just change the rest of my life to make them happen (wrt travel vs eating out all the time).
What’s great is, I can let that shit fall away from me easily nowadays.
I hear it, I recognize the kind of effect it’s had on me at various points in my life, and I let it fall to the wayside.
Jonny Dee is a smart man, he’s encountered a lot over his life, and I value his wit and wisdom, but like so many pseudo-negative aspects of my life, I have to be willing to say, ``No, I don’t need to accept this as my current truth'' the way I did in high school or college or after college.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-06-pain/</guid><link>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-06-pain/</link><title>Pain</title><description>I don’t know what I’m here to write, I just know that I have this feeling like I should keep it up.
So here I am, writing more.What’s the point of writing for one’s self? Reflection? I don’t get my actual feelings out if I’m not conversing with someone.
Julie talks about reading her journals from when she went to therapy early in her relationship with Jon and how much clarity she finds in it, how nice it is to see the clear lines of work and effort and thought that went into various decisions in her life.
I don’t do that.
Maybe I should? I honestly don’t find it compelling to write for myself.
The kinds of thoughts that I write don’t accurately represent me internally in a given moment.
Maybe like a sign post signifying the general area it might be helpful to write the various interpretations I’ve created from parts of my life, and then look back on them later, saying, "Ah from this vantage point, I can see the shape of the land, the whole from all of the pieces I could barely consider when in the tasks and minutia."</description><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-07-30-marriage/</guid><link>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-07-30-marriage/</link><title>Marriage</title><description>I’m at this weird crossroads in my life right now, where I can push hard to get married and settle down, and I could also dive back into the "dating" life I led in the winter/spring months.
After lots of hemming and hawing, I had some excellent conversations with Ally on Friday night and Saturday morning, which has led me to the conclusion that I should get married.
I should ask May, in fact, to marry me.I "preposed" to May on Saturday night, after we smanged.
Almost said it during, but I had the good sense to wait until we were cuddling afterwards.
Honestly, I’m a fool with timing.
Thankfully, The Kindest Human, May, responded very positively and generously, considering that I had informally asked her to consider marrying me.
We’re having a conversation tomorrow evening (2017-07-31T20:30 ish).
I hope it goes well, and based on the comments we’ve made to each other, I suspect the smanging will eclipse the marriage talk, lol.</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-07-29-intro/</guid><link>http://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-07-29-intro/</link><title>Intro</title><description>Starting any project is difficult, and I suspect regular blogging is not an activity I’ll have much luck with, seeing as I’ve classically hated all forms of writing.
However, along with the work in self-care and Success Oriented Mindset I’ve implemented over the last year, I think it’s time to attempt to conquer this issue as well.Also, at this point, all I have to do is twist something into a vaguely "programmery" design, and I fall head-over-heals into it, desperate for any reason to apply my skills at programming, even when I have no idea what I’m doing.</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>