<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://noahtheduke.github.io/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Thoughts and bits</title><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 21:55:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-11-i-m-moving-all-of-my/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-11-i-m-moving-all-of-my/</link><title>i'm moving all of my coposts to my blog</title><description>is this a good idea? idk. but i like all my posts here and i don't wanna lose em. i really tried hard to post more and think less; it's up to you to determine if i was successful.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 21:25:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-11-blog/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-11-blog/</link><title>blog</title><description>as the world (cohost) ends, you can check my blogging at https://noahtheduke.github.io/, which i have updated and will be moving all of my posting to once this burns away.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 04:40:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-10-remember-them-here/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-10-remember-them-here/</link><title>remember them? here they are now! feel old yet?</title><description></description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 17:19:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-10-i-guess-i-should-mak/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-10-i-guess-i-should-mak/</link><title>i guess i should make a blog, huh</title><description>i've got a github pages blog, but that's tied down to github. i can buy a domain name fairly easily, but i gotta point it at something. what i need is a server i guess??? to run my shit. maybe digital ocean, heroku, etc. i asked back in march about self-hosting but didn't follow through because i'm weak.what's your hosting set up? how do you run yours? have any hot tips for a programmer who doesn't know shit about devops?</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 15:50:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-10-yesterday-was-the-3/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-10-yesterday-was-the-3/</link><title>yesterday was the 3 year anniversary of my wife's moms death</title><description>felt appropriate for cohost to announce the shutdown on the same day.a day of mourning and a day of reminiscing and a day of telling stories about what has come and what might come. we cleaned her gravestone, set up some halloween decorations and flowers, ate her favorite candy, and talked about how much she would have loved to see the kids get bigger.i wish i could have known her longer.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 14:09:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-08-splint-release-auto/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-08-splint-release-auto/</link><title>splint release: autocorrection bby</title><description>Big feature: Safety and AutocorrectionEvery rule has been marked as safe or unsafe. Safe rules don't generate false positives and any suggested alternatives can be used directly. Unsafe rules may generate false positives or their suggested alternatives may contain errors.Rules that are safe may also perform autocorrection, which is tracked in defrule with :autocorrect. Rules may only perform autocorrection if they're safe.</description><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 20:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-06-i-don-t-mind-the-cea/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-06-i-don-t-mind-the-cea/</link><title>i don't mind the ceaseless passage of time but i really wish i cold remember the past better</title><description>i'm glad my kids are growing up, i don't want them to be this age forever. however, i wish i could hold them when they were so very tiny again.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 04:19:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-05-clojure-1-12-release/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-09-05-clojure-1-12-release/</link><title>Clojure 1.12 released!!!</title><description>https://clojure.org/news/2024/09/05/clojure-1-12-0I'm excited as hell for this one. The qualified method syntax along with treating Java methods as first-class values means that writing interop will be much nicer. :param-tags letting you differentiate between overloads is killer too. The longer I've spent in Clojure, the more Java I've had to wrangle, and these have been big pain points.</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 20:25:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-30-jedi-survivor-play-r/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-30-jedi-survivor-play-r/</link><title>Jedi Survivor play report</title><description>Started playing Jedi Survivor after burning out on Elden Ring again.This game is a blast. The grappling hook feels  great, the writing is fun, Cameron Monaghan's voice acting is a little subdued for my tastes but that's okay. new force powers are odd, still getting used to them, but the split blade is sick.there's freaking battle droids in this one, so we get their chatter!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!! 10/10 game</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 12:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-25-updated-my-backloggd/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-25-updated-my-backloggd/</link><title>updated my backloggd</title><description>went through steam and howlongtobeat and my playstation 5 and my switch, added nearly everything. i've got a lot of fuckin games, maybe i should play them some time.anyone have a good way to work through a back log? maybe a randomizer? it seems backloggd doesn't support something natively, and my google searches proved fruitless.</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 14:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-25-ps5/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-25-ps5/</link><title>ps5</title><description>why the fuck do i need to download a game that's on the goddamn disc onto my console. just play the game like every other console for the last 40 years. now i gotta juggle installs??? buy an external hard drive??? just play the fucking game bro. "ooooh but it's hard to load things from the disc" just put less shit in the game. make it smaller, use fewer 1 gig textures. it's not hard, in fact it's much easier to do less and make less stuff. i know because i do less every day, i under achieve on purpose and it's quite nice.</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-25-div-style-display/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-25-div-style-display/</link><title></title><description>NoahTheDukereviewed Uncharted 2: Among Thieves RemasteredCompletedonPlayStation 4
								A perfectly fine way to spend some evenings. The action/adventure sequences are fun, the set pieces are still beautiful, the occasional funny quip, but the rest is forgettable.Mushy controls, worse combat, threadbare stealth, along with another Nathan Drake story that didn't hold much weight. I played it on easy because I don't think this is worth any effort especially if you've played The Last of Us which is better in almost every way. (I will say that Nathan Drake sucks less than Joel, the worst human alive.)I love Elena tho, she's my ride or die.
							Reviewed on Aug 25, 2024</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 02:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2024-08-24-uncharted-2-review/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2024-08-24-uncharted-2-review/</link><title>Review: Uncharted 2</title><description>NoahTheDukereviewed Uncharted 2: Among Thieves RemasteredCompletedonPlayStation 4
								A perfectly fine way to spend some evenings. The action/adventure sequences are fun, the set pieces are still beautiful, the occasional funny quip, but the rest is forgettable.Mushy controls, worse combat, threadbare stealth, along with another Nathan Drake story that didn't hold much weight. I played it on easy because I don't think this is worth any effort especially if you've played The Last of Us which is better in almost every way. (I will say that Nathan Drake sucks less than Joel, the worst human alive.)I love Elena tho, she's my ride or die.
							Reviewed on Aug 25, 2024</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 22:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-23-i-ve-got-good-news-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-23-i-ve-got-good-news-a/</link><title>i've got good news and bad news, chat</title><description>good news: i'm gonna sign a job offer on monday.bad news: it's a permanent 1099 (contractor-style) position, so now i gotta fuck with taxes.good news: it's $80/hr.</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 23:09:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-22-cw-suicidal-ideatio/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-22-cw-suicidal-ideatio/</link><title></title><description>me when i have a job: i think i'm just naturally happy. i don't get sad often or for long periods and i easily roll with the punches of day to day life.me when i don't have a job: maybe i should kill myself.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 16:12:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-20-it-s-been-2-months-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-20-it-s-been-2-months-a/</link><title></title><description>it's been 2 months and i'm still jobless. what the fuck am i gonna do?</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 22:11:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-20-ocaml-wishlist/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-20-ocaml-wishlist/</link><title>Ocaml wishlist</title><description>On twitter, someone asked: "But seriously, what changes would you make to OCaml which would worth it to break backward compatibility?"I replied with: "Borrow from Clojure! 1) Make (=) / polymorphic equality work on values (not structure). 2) Make "functional updates" of records nicer. 3) Change ref to work like clj atoms, add swap! as a built-in function. 4) Remove the mutable keyword, make ref the only mutating interface."Our very own @prophet responded ([1], [2], [3], [4]):</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 19:52:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-17-not-to-be-a-hater-bu/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-17-not-to-be-a-hater-bu/</link><title>not to be a hater but...</title><description>mistborn fuckin sucks, dude. i'm 100 pages in and i'm already over it. the writing is really bad, plodding, obvious. he has a way of writing dialogue that feels like he's got a movie playing in his mind and is trying desperately to transcribe it one to one, but imo that's not how quality fiction works.everyone's smiling or their existing smiles are deepening, they're stroking their chins, they're asking with surprise, they're nodding and shaking their head or thinning their eyes or pausing or glancing or scowling. it feels like all of the mid fan fiction i've ever read.not everyone needs to write like cormac mccarthy but come the fuck on</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 20:28:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-17-i-can-t-stop-thinkin/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-17-i-can-t-stop-thinkin/</link><title></title><description>I can't stop thinking about this post by
Hillel Wayne: "You do not prove something's correct. You prove conformance to specification."What are you gaining and what are you losing with your chosen specification?https://buttondown.com/hillelwayne/archive/testing-can-show-the-presence-of-bugs-but-not-the/</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 13:39:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-15-i-should-probably-st/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-15-i-should-probably-st/</link><title>i should probably stop reading programming twitter. bunch of turgid self assured jackasses loudly stating opinions as facts</title><description>this isn't really about static vs dynamic typing but that is the current thing, and it's exhausting seeing everyone try their best to dunk on and mock and deride everyone else who disagrees with them. like yes, you think people who use static typing are weak losers, or you think people who use dynamic typing are morons who are too lazy to type a couple extra characters. Good job, everyone! You all suck ass and actively make the art of programming worse for all involved.fuck you</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 02:44:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-13-almost-drowned-in-la/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-13-almost-drowned-in-la/</link><title></title><description>almost drowned in Lake Michigan today. AMA</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 23:38:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-09-idk-if-i-ll-ever-be/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-09-idk-if-i-ll-ever-be/</link><title>idk if i'll ever be as disappointed by an album as i was with glitch mob's love death immortality</title><description>after drink the sea (nearly perfect), i went in with such high hopes and yet even 10 years later, love death immortality just fucking sucks dude. not a single good song, almost none of the things that made me love drink the sea, just a complete abdication of their sound and style.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 04:50:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-08-splint-v1-16-0/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-08-splint-v1-16-0/</link><title>Splint v1.16.0</title><description>The --only cli flag is one I've been meaning to implement for a while but just hadn't gotten around to. It's really only helpful when you're zeroing in on a problem rule, but there will always be uses.The rule lint/duplicate-case-test is already checked by case's expansion, but I think it's good for static analysis tools to verify that stuff too. And lint/locking-object should help uncover subtle bugs, especially in concurrent situations.Honestly, having been fired, I just don't have the strong drive to work on this like I did. I no longer have a 140k sloc project to test against, so there's less for me to look at and find inspiration from. I'm trying to keep up with it tho, it's helpful to not get rusty.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 15:42:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-07-so-where-are-y-all-l/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-07-so-where-are-y-all-l/</link><title></title><description>So where are y'all looking for software jobs? How do you find openings? LinkedIn is only so-so, and dice and indeed and monster are worse than they've ever been. I'm now 1.5 months into unemployment and it's rough out here.If we get to September, my wife will have to go back to work (making 1/3 of my previous salary) and then we'll really be in a bind as I have to take time away from job hunting to take care of the kids. I know I made a significant sum at my last job so I've been dramatically lowering my expectations, and yet I'm still finding myself rejected for not doing enough "enterprise software" in my career. Every company in Cincinnati is looking for 3-5 years of Java and Spring/Spring Boot lmao. Working in such an environment would kill me, but I'd do it because I need a job more than I need to be comfortable. Lots of "3-5 years C#".</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 19:29:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-06-cohost-is-kill/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-06-cohost-is-kill/</link><title>cohost is kill</title><description>can't add tags to my posts :eggbug-sob:</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:24:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-06-critique-my-ocaml/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-06-critique-my-ocaml/</link><title>critique my ocaml</title><description>https://github.com/NoahTheDuke/ahrefsi applied to ahrefs and the first step was this challenge. i suspect a more seasoned ocaml programmer could have done it faster than i, but i've also never done any socket programming, so there were a lot of things to learn all at once.gimme your feedback! even tho i doubt i'll get the job, i'm interested in continuing to use Ocaml. it's fun to push myself into new things!</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-06-https-x-com-x-daily/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-08-06-https-x-com-x-daily/</link><title></title><description>https://x.com/xDaily/status/1820634359306563720can't believe el*n is now cribbing from cohost.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 03:11:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-27-flower-the-skunk-is/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-27-flower-the-skunk-is/</link><title></title><description>flower the skunk is queer, right?</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 23:25:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-27-me-i-m-going-to-vol/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-27-me-i-m-going-to-vol/</link><title></title><description>me: i'm going to volunteer my time to try to make something better with no expectation of acceptance. this is a gift alone.also me: why aren't the reviewers reviewing this pr fast enough???</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 22:56:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-26-i-know-it-s-not-the/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-26-i-know-it-s-not-the/</link><title></title><description>I know it's not the style, but I like to think of Ocaml like a Clojure that has more syntax, and just wrap everything in parentheses. Every function call, every assignment, every if block, everything.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-26-i-only-started-learn/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-26-i-only-started-learn/</link><title></title><description>i only started learning Ocaml on Wednesday, but i'm already opening PRs to help improve the documentation on the ocaml.org site: https://github.com/ocaml/ocaml.org/pull/2613contributing to open source just feels good, what can i say?it is moderately funny and fucked up that until now, there's not one droplet of information about comments on the ocaml website.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 17:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-25-i-wanna-carry-a-knif/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-25-i-wanna-carry-a-knif/</link><title></title><description>i wanna carry a knife. what should i get?</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 04:07:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-24-learning-a-new-progr/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-24-learning-a-new-progr/</link><title></title><description>learning a new programming language is like walking into a world where your mom's house is mirrored</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 21:10:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-24-so-it-would-seem-to/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-24-so-it-would-seem-to/</link><title></title><description>So it would seem to be true
When cruel birth debases, we forget
When cruel death debases
We believe it erases all the rest
That precedesBut stand brave, life-liver
Bleeding out your days
In the river of time
Stand brave
Time moves both waysIn the nullifying, defeating, negating, repeating
Joy of life</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 15:52:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-24-empty/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-24-empty/</link><title></title><description></description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 01:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-23-elden-ring-is-a-myst/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-23-elden-ring-is-a-myst/</link><title></title><description>elden ring is a myst-like more than it's a souls game</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 03:20:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-22-tu-gato-es-un-chad-o/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-22-tu-gato-es-un-chad-o/</link><title>Tu gato es un Chad o un beta?</title><description>Tu gato es un Chad o un beta?</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 23:12:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-22-i-ve-been-ghosted-by/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-22-i-ve-been-ghosted-by/</link><title>i've been ghosted by a job</title><description>a recruiter at a company reached out to me on linkedin, and then i went through 3 rounds of interviews at the company (including a very small coding challenge), and now it's been a week and i've not heard anything from them. i reached out the same day to say how well it went, i emailed two days later to check in, and then hit up the recruiter on linkedin at the end of the week, and crickets.shit sucks, yo. i don't mind the time spent (i'm jobless, i've got nothing but time), but the lack of decency to let me know what's going on??? it's shameful and disheartening.if you don't like my work or think i'm not a fit, you can write a single sentence: "Thanks for your time, but we've decided to go with another candidate." you can flower it up all you want, but that's the bare bones what to say! just say that dude, no need to be like this.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 15:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-20-the-worst-part-of-ge/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-20-the-worst-part-of-ge/</link><title>the worst part of getting a new tattoo is scheduling</title><description>which is to say, i'd have so many more if i didn't have to get in contact with an artist (impossible), discuss the idea (easy), and then schedule the appointment (hard).this is why my last 3 have been from flashes</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 21:23:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-16-people-should-read-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-16-people-should-read-a/</link><title>people should read aftermath</title><description>i won't tear down polygon, but i will say that freed from the demands of "hitting numbers", the content on aftermath.site is consistently better and more interesting than on the big name sites.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:33:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-09-finally-got-a-win-wi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-09-finally-got-a-win-wi/</link><title>Finally got a win with Isaac and the Jupiter</title><description>built a glass cannon: lots of damage, most everything piercing, overdrive and powerdrive, and use artifacts to get evade and shift. buckshot b was the star of the show with 3 piercing 0s bumped to 1 with powerdrive and then increased to 3 with overpower a. if i could get two jupiter drones on the field, that's an incredible amount of damage in one turn.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 03:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-08-i-think-if-your-game/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-08-i-think-if-your-game/</link><title>i think if your game has a store page that's anything like this, you should be hung from the neck until dead in a public square at noon</title><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 14:52:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-08-no-shade-to-the-othe/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-08-no-shade-to-the-othe/</link><title>no shade to the other artists but Hideki Naganuma's songs on the bomb rush cyberfunk soundtrack are the best.</title><description>top 101-3) Hideki Naganuma's songs
4) 2 Mello's I Wann Kno
5) Klaus Veen's Anime Break
6) Reso's Chuckin Up
7) PROUX's Funk Express
8) Reso's Iridium
9) Reso's Spectres
10) Olli's Precious Thing</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 14:39:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-08-help-me-remember-a-g/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-08-help-me-remember-a-g/</link><title>help me remember a game</title><description>i played this on my windows xp desktop in the early 00s. blocky 3d. there's a bug/insect-like creature or robot that wanders aimlessly through a level and you have to click on parts of the environment to set it up to help the bug progress. you click a block to move it in front of water to keep the bug from being washed away. you click a platform when the bug steps on it to make it raise like an elevator. etc. your goal is to keeps it alive and help it get to the end of the level. i remember it looking like Dark Forces 2: Jedi Knight, but much uglier.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:43:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-07-i-hate-when-i-m-so-t/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-07-i-hate-when-i-m-so-t/</link><title></title><description>i hate when i'm so tired i fall asleep standing up but taking caffeine only gives me a headache</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 21:24:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-06-funny-thing-has-been/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-07-06-funny-thing-has-been/</link><title></title><description>funny thing has been happening with reviews i've seen of Animal Well: people have been missing small but critical parts of the game in their playground because it's deliberately obtuse and designed to be discovered through play. this has soured some folks on it (such as my brother) who spend 2-5 hours at some part of the game just running around not knowing what to do until someone tells them "you missed x" and then they beat the game shortly after and are like "that was a waste of time" turning a 9/10 to a 6/10.however, that has repeatedly been my experience of elden ring. i have consistently missed sign posts, quest lines, critical paths because i'm just playing the game and then i'm wandering around like "what do i do now?" it's not exactly unpleasant but it does kill the enthusiasm and fun while it's happening, and then i'm annoyed when i post in my group chat and someone says "you missed x." but none of the reviews for elden ring i saw mentioned this or were like "it's deeply unpleasant to play without a guide or friend who has already played it."i'm not gonna say double standard, but it seems people are more lenient about dumb bullshit in a fromsoft game than an indie game.</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 23:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-30-lacuna-a-sci-fi-no/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-30-lacuna-a-sci-fi-no/</link><title>Lacuna - A Sci Fi Noir Adventure</title><description>I played and beat Lacuna this week. Incredible little game. I guessed the big revelation during the prologue so that didn't hit so hard, but the rest was a delight. The way the cases and sheets are filled out was at first really hard and then much easier and more fun as the game went on. I thought i'd gotten everything right and then learned that I missed whole branches because i'd some early mistakes. Feels pretty great, especially for such a short and punchy game.Excellent music and soundtrack, beautiful pixel art, compelling universe. I was sad to finish the game, I want to spend more time here.</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 12:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-24-lost-my-job-today/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-24-lost-my-job-today/</link><title>lost my job today</title><description>thankfully, it was due to general capitalism bs (company bought another company and had to make "cuts") and not because they hated my fuckin guts lolbut now i'm stuck working my least favorite job, "finding a new job". truly an annoying situation. i hope i can find something fast enough that we don't lose too much of our savings, cuz i still really wanna buy a minivan.</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 19:57:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-18-i-love-calling-someo/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-18-i-love-calling-someo/</link><title>i love calling someone with a hindu nationalist flag profile pic a nazi lmao</title><description>they're like "how dare you! the swastika is cultural! it's the original meaning!" and i'm like "the ethnic cleaning of muslims is cultural?" and then they call me a racist.are they technically nazis? no, of course not, but violent fascists focused on racial and religious purity tend to mimic each other.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 23:41:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-16-paper-chat-gpt-is-b/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-16-paper-chat-gpt-is-b/</link><title>Paper: "ChatGPT is bullshit"</title><description>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10676-024-09775-5Abstract:Recently, there has been considerable interest in large language models: machine learning systems which produce human-like text and dialogue. Applications of these systems have been plagued by persistent inaccuracies in their output; these are often called “AI hallucinations”. We argue that these falsehoods, and the overall activity of large language models, is better understood as bullshit in the sense explored by Frankfurt (On Bullshit, Princeton, 2005): the models are in an important way indifferent to the truth of their outputs. We distinguish two ways in which the models can be said to be bullshitters, and argue that they clearly meet at least one of these definitions. We further argue that describing AI misrepresentations as bullshit is both a more useful and more accurate way of predicting and discussing the behaviour of these systems.</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 02:16:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-14-bridgerton-season-3/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-14-bridgerton-season-3/</link><title>bridgerton season 3</title><description>omg that penelope/colin sex scene was incredible. hottest thing they've done yet.</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 12:24:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-10-i-dropped-my-iphone/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-10-i-dropped-my-iphone/</link><title></title><description>i dropped my iphone nearly a week ago, busted the screen just enough that it no longer registers touches. so i swapped the sim into a flip phone and have been living an offline life.lemme tell you what, it's a pretty sick life. i'm slowly losing the sense of "i'm bored for 2 seconds, lemme look at my phone" which has been the bane of my adhd-riddled existence for 15 years.the flip phone uses KaiOS which is based on the firefox os lol, so it has no good apps and runs like shit, but honestly, having more friction means that i can't/won't load it up with a bunch of stuff. all i do is text my wife and make calls to places, which is ideal.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 15:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-07-github-as-myspace/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-07-github-as-myspace/</link><title>github as myspace</title><description>this is art</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 19:23:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-04-artist-alley-continu/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-04-artist-alley-continu/</link><title>artist alley continues to provide</title><description> </description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 18:18:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-03-disenchantment/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-03-disenchantment/</link><title>Disenchantment</title><description>watched the final season after taking a year off. what a good fuckin show.i loved every happy ending, tbh. felt perfectly inline with the show for everyone to live happily ever after.this is the best show matt groening has ever done, by far.</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 03:50:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-01-hr-i-lived-bitch/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-06-01-hr-i-lived-bitch/</link><title></title><description>i lived bitch</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 17:08:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-28-i-am-so-into-my-wife/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-28-i-am-so-into-my-wife/</link><title>i am so into my wife, dude</title><description>idk how to write it. i'm not a poet, i was raised by a writer but words don't come easily to me so when i feel these feelings, all i come up with is stuff like "she's so fucking hot" which is true but also shallow.it's like...every texture of her body is built to electrify me. each line, each curve, each shadow pulls me in. i feel suffocated by her, like she enters the room and my lungs fill with cotton. i want every square inch of her body in my mouth at once. i see her and it makes me lose my train of thought, i can't focus on anything else. i want to be enveloped by her, smothered and wrapped up and ensconced. i try to alight on a solid fantasy but they merge and meld and flow into the next too fast to hold for more than a moment.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-25-if-you-are-part-of-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-25-if-you-are-part-of-a/</link><title></title><description>if you are part of any decision making process that forbids trees and/or grass from playgrounds, i hope you fucking [violates facebook community standards]if you are part of any litigation against owners of playgrounds related to the presence of trees at a playground (a kid got hurt climbing a tree etc), i hope you fucking [violates facebook community standards]if you think that barren playgrounds, fully exposed to the sun and covered in heat absorbing plastic, are enjoyable for children, i hope you fucking [violates facebook community standards]</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 18:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-25-going-to-shows-alone/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-25-going-to-shows-alone/</link><title></title><description>going to shows alone sucks</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 01:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-19-cw-early-tomie-spoi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-19-cw-early-tomie-spoi/</link><title></title><description>i'm four chapters in and i don't get it. the art is great, really striking and beautiful and grotesque. but the characters don't make any sense and the plots don't make any sense.why is everyone's first idea "stab" or "cut into pieces"? the first chapter was very hard to read, basically incomprehensible character motivations. the second was going along fine until the stabbing and then it fell off the rails. the third started off insane with the regrowth but then there's a dude in the closet??? the conversion to tomie is fun, i liked that, but the basement stuff (more cutting into pieces) felt out of nowhere.who are these people? why are they doing anything they're doing? i want to be scared, but i'm so confused that i'm actually laughing out loud.</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 04:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-17-only-through-repetit/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-17-only-through-repetit/</link><title>only through repetition do we grow</title><description>you know those cooking shows where they travel to some remote countryside place and interview a woman who's been making a certain bread for 50 years and is now old and frail but she's still got it, by god.and they're like "what's your secret?" and she's like "i've been making this bread every day for fifty years" and they're like "there you have it, folks, the secret is the kind of flour she uses."</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 04:46:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-05-look-at-these-bookma/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-05-look-at-these-bookma/</link><title>look at these bookmarks i found on artist alley!</title><description>they're so beautiful. thanks, @asher!</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 13:09:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-05-wife-i-m-putting-th/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-05-wife-i-m-putting-th/</link><title></title><description>wife: i'm putting this away because you keep doing what i've asked you to not do. your actions have consequences, [daughter].
4 year old: no! they! don't!!!!!!</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 13:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-04-i-know-it-s-somewhat/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-04-i-know-it-s-somewhat/</link><title></title><description>i know it's somewhat human nature to want to proselytize things you enjoy, but it's very silly/deeply weird to see people into niche sex activities be like "i want to tell people all about being X. what are good ways to broach the topic with my friends?" when X is like fisting or being anal exclusive.</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-04-can-t-wait-to-learn/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-04-can-t-wait-to-learn/</link><title>can't wait to learn about computers and microprocessors. i hope to someday become a programmer</title><description></description><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 20:13:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-01-splint-v1-15-0-cus/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-01-splint-v1-15-0-cus/</link><title>splint v1.15.0 - custom rules support!</title><description>I've been sitting on this release for a little while now, trying to find the right way to approach to supporting custom rules.The way the rules work currently, when a file with defrule is evaluated, the defrule macro adds the generated rule to a global atom. This simplifies a lot of stuff in the codebase, and makes adding new rules to splint pretty easy: make a new file, require it in the entrypoint for the library. However, users can't access that entrypoint from the cli, and while I've not exactly hidden the code, I don't think people should have to write their own entrypoint wrappers merely to include their own rules.Inspired by RuboCop YET AGAIN, I've added a new option, settable in the config file or by passing the relevant flag at the cli, to call load-file on a given set of files which will presumably call their custom defrule invocations. Because I'm relying on Clojure's built-in behavior, there is no extra code necessary for me to parse or validate the paths myself; I pass them to load-file in a loop and print any exceptions that are thrown.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 18:07:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-01-open-source-maintena/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-05-01-open-source-maintena/</link><title>open source maintenance</title><description>i am the maintainer of the vim syntax highlighting file for just, vim-just, and while i did the heavy lifting to write up the initial version back in 2021, i haven't cared much about keeping up with the latest changes and have let others make changes as they do.last year, someone offered to help out so i added them to the repo. i suspect it's their first time being a "contributor" on an open source project cuz they've spent the last year absolutely dedicated to the task of improving both the syntax highlighting and the bespoke syntax test runner we have that's written in rust. the project isn't that exciting and doesn't require that much effort but they've stayed up to date (to the day) of new syntaxes added to just and have been poking and prodding the test runner to make it faster and more idiomatic, including writing their own custom version of vim's built-in :ToHtml as it was removed in neovim. today, they mentioned "but we don't want code like this in production" which cracked me up because there's no "production" to be had here! doesn't matter, they give a shit and so i give a shit with them.there's no real point here, it's just fun to see someone really dive in and own something. i know open source maintenance is a touchy subject after the xz/liblzma stuff, but i still think it's worthwhile to give people a chance to make their mark and spend their effort on cool things.</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 15:36:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-29-see-things-for-what/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-29-see-things-for-what/</link><title></title><description>See things for what they are and what they're not
There's no desire without fear
Afraid of losing, afraid of satisfaction</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 03:53:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-26-https-www-youtube/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-26-https-www-youtube/</link><title></title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YUb7QY1T4Wk</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 03:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-24-from-the-great-dicta/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-24-from-the-great-dicta/</link><title>from The Great Dictator</title><description>I’m sorry, but I don’t want to be an emperor. That’s not my business. I don’t want to rule or conquer anyone. I should like to help everyone - if possible - Jew, Gentile - black man - white. We all want to help one another. Human beings are like that. We want to live by each other’s happiness - not by each other’s misery. We don’t want to hate and despise one another. In this world there is room for everyone. And the good earth is rich and can provide for everyone. The way of life can be free and beautiful, but we have lost the way.Greed has poisoned men’s souls, has barricaded the world with hate, has goose-stepped us into misery and bloodshed. We have developed speed, but we have shut ourselves in. Machinery that gives abundance has left us in want. Our knowledge has made us cynical. Our cleverness, hard and unkind. We think too much and feel too little. More than machinery we need humanity. More than cleverness we need kindness and gentleness. Without these qualities, life will be violent and all will be lost…The aeroplane and the radio have brought us closer together. The very nature of these inventions cries out for the goodness in men - cries out for universal brotherhood - for the unity of us all. Even now my voice is reaching millions throughout the world - millions of despairing men, women, and little children - victims of a system that makes men torture and imprison innocent people.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 21:29:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-24-my-wife-and-i-just-p/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-24-my-wife-and-i-just-p/</link><title></title><description>my wife and i just played rock paper scissors to decide who has to run out for oreos and we tied 4 rounds in a row: scissors rock scissors rock</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-19-i-fell-asleep-before/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-19-i-fell-asleep-before/</link><title></title><description>i fell asleep before it released at midnight, so now i can enjoy all 2 hours as a single unit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 11:40:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-17-sometimes-when-my-wi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-17-sometimes-when-my-wi/</link><title></title><description>sometimes when my wife chastises our kids, i feel the embarrassment i felt when a friend's mom would chastise them in front of me lol</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 22:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-16-cw-miscarriage/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-16-cw-miscarriage/</link><title></title><description>my wife is experiencing a miscarriage right now. all either of us can do when we're alone together is hug and cry.be at peace, baby, and be gone</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 21:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-15-i-know-it-s-still-ea/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-15-i-know-it-s-still-ea/</link><title></title><description>i know it's still early in the year, but deeper well by kacey musgraves is an early contender for album of the year. it's so pleasant with a nice mix of poignant songs.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 04:14:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-14-4-y-o-it-s-sticky-i/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-14-4-y-o-it-s-sticky-i/</link><title></title><description>4 y/o: it's sticky in the hospital
me: oh yeah? is it your breath in the mask?
her: no, i farted</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 16:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-13-4-y-o-comes-into-the/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-13-4-y-o-comes-into-the/</link><title></title><description>4 y/o comes into the bathroom while i'm pooping, says "it smells bad in here, yuck" then tries to turn the light off when she leaves</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 13:04:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-12-me-about-clem/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-12-me-about-clem/</link><title>me about clem</title><description></description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 05:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-11-todays-gender-mike/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-11-todays-gender-mike/</link><title>todays gender: mike portnoy's drums in constant motion during the solo</title><description>https://youtu.be/EjtfpfW-Ogk</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 01:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-10-can-t-believe-i-have/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-10-can-t-believe-i-have/</link><title>can't believe i have to wait until at minimum next year for another vanessa carlton album</title><description>the spaces between her albums keep increasing, 2 3 4 4 5, and nothing's been announced or even hinted at, so i'm just here waiting...</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 18:29:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-10-mental-math-pseudo-r/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-10-mental-math-pseudo-r/</link><title>Mental Math Pseudo Random Number Generation</title><description>&gt; given a large prime p, a multiplier m, and a seed number x_0, a Lehmer PRNG can be defined by the recursive function x_{n+1} = m \cdot x_n \mod p.> One pair choice is p=59, m=6. Because 60 \equiv 1 \mod 59, each iteration is a simple matter of multiplying the ones digit by 6 and adding the tens digit. To illustrate, a sequence starting from 17 would continue 43, 22, 14, 25, 32, 15, 31, 9, 54, 29, ..., and taking just the unit's digit, that turns into 3, 2, 4, 5, 2, 5, 1, 9, 4, 9, which looks pretty random.> Next up is p=101, m=50. Because p=101, this construction has the advantage that the sequence goes from 1 to 100, making the distribution of the output stream uniform over 1 to 10 and providing a longer period. The choice of multiplier also simplifies computation: if the current state x_i is even, the next number x_{i+1} = 101 - \frac{2}, and if odd, x_{i+1} = 50 - \frac{2}. Not as nice as the previous example, but still not bad.</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 04:39:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-09-bought-a-new-hat-at/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-09-bought-a-new-hat-at/</link><title>Bought a new hat at the Indy children’s museum</title><description>Might be the nerdiest clothing I own.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 20:58:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-08-total-eclipse-of-the/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-08-total-eclipse-of-the/</link><title></title><description>Total eclipse of the shart</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 19:24:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-08-this-was-hell-505-d/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-08-this-was-hell-505-d/</link><title></title><description>This was hell. 505 day streak</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 01:51:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-08-4-y-o-papa-can-we/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-08-4-y-o-papa-can-we/</link><title></title><description>4 y/o: papa, can we get [toy on tv]?
Me: No.
4 y/o: momma, don’t listen to papa. Can we get [toy on tv]?</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 01:13:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-07-nothing-worse-than-m/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-07-nothing-worse-than-m/</link><title></title><description>Nothing worse than making a great joke in the group chat and only getting heart reacts.</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 01:26:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-06-sex-and-the-city-is/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-06-sex-and-the-city-is/</link><title>Sex and the City is dated and honestly hard to watch</title><description>it does have some banger lines, tho: "sweetheart, that's all very nice but if you're not going to eat pussy, you're not a dyke.”</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 16:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-05-just-learned-that-m/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-05-just-learned-that-m/</link><title></title><description>Just learned that M.I.A. was outspoken against the covid vaccine. 😩</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 12:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-05-shift-leaders-are-cl/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-05-shift-leaders-are-cl/</link><title></title><description>Shift leaders are class traitors.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 12:14:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-04-i-ve-been-sitting-on/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-04-i-ve-been-sitting-on/</link><title></title><description>I’ve been sitting on the seed of a blog post for a minute that goes something like “modern civil rights activists/sjws hurt their messaging by trying to redefine the word “racism” to mean systemic racism instead of the colloquial definition of interpersonal race-based prejudice.” Because I’m not a writer i don’t have a lot else to say about it yet lol but it’s been bouncing around in my brain for like 3 years.i’m mostly writing this now to incentivize writing more later. tired of merely thinking this</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 23:39:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-04-my-wife-are-you-a-p/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-04-my-wife-are-you-a-p/</link><title></title><description>my wife: are you a pretty boy? yes yes
2 y/o: no, i hanome hucky
her: you're a handsome hunky?
him: yeah!!!!!!</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 18:29:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-04-cannot-believe-rob-d/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-04-cannot-believe-rob-d/</link><title>cannot believe rob dropped an "anne of green gables" reference in the manaan episode of amca</title><description>everyone's roasting him but i knew it! i picked it up!!!!!! anne stans rise up!!!!!!!!!!!!!!</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 16:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-04-the-ones-who-walk-aw/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-04-the-ones-who-walk-aw/</link><title></title><description>The Ones Who Walk Away From Rosas</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 12:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-03-happy-day-in-our-hou/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-03-happy-day-in-our-hou/</link><title>Happy day in our house: Wish has come to Disney+</title><description></description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 19:24:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-03-i-picked-up-going-un/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-04-03-i-picked-up-going-un/</link><title>I picked up Going Under again, a good little podcast game</title><description>NoahTheDukereviewed Going UnderCompletedonNintendo Switch
								I cranked up the accessibility features cuz I already put 20 hours in and never got close to finishing it, and I certainly haven’t gotten better in the intervening years lol.This game is pretty good. Cute writing, fairly obvious and funny commentary on start ups and VC culture. The “corporate art” style is killer, imo. Really pops, gives everything a sense of place. The soundtrack is a lot of fun too.I’m playing on the Switch and I must say that it’s fairly choppy/framey. Not unsurprising given the hardware’s age, but it still struggles to show a fight with a handful of enemies and some fire effects without stuttering.
							Reviewed on Apr 03, 2024</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 03:42:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-29-new-adrian-berenguer/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-29-new-adrian-berenguer/</link><title>New Adrián Berenguer!!!!!</title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wtcU42rthCM</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 15:32:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-28-taken-from-stimslack/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-28-taken-from-stimslack/</link><title>Taken from stimslack</title><description></description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 17:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-28-chappell-roan-cali/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-28-chappell-roan-cali/</link><title>Chappell Roan - California</title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GcXlN7meclECome get me out of California
No leaves are brown
I miss the seasons in Missouri
My dying town
Thought I'd be cool in California
I'd make you proud
To think I almost had it going
But I let you downshit's got me cryin</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 13:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-28-my-2-y-o-was-stresse/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-28-my-2-y-o-was-stresse/</link><title>My 2 y/o was STRESSED last night</title><description>Things he shouted out at various points of his sleep:</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 13:19:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-28-https-github-com-m/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-28-https-github-com-m/</link><title></title><description>https://github.com/mtgred/netrunner/pull/7346this shit is another hefty one. i rewrote the primary data structure for costs. will be much simpler to track costs, add modifiers later, keep normal and additional costs distinct, and intelligently handle stealth costs.once this is done, i'm gonna implement system-wide additional cost checking, allowing you to reject paying for any and all additional costs.</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 05:29:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-27-https-youtu-be-6oq/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-27-https-youtu-be-6oq/</link><title></title><description>https://youtu.be/6oqO3FXSecMall i could think while watching this wasIt's a joint project between Nideo and the Frontier Syndicate. They're inventing the perfect city, a Divine city, the Divine City. The city city. City: The City. What's past a Divine? The City. The City. City City is the next City to be built on Palisade. It's also the next City to be built on Palisade. City City is the future. City City is the Past, capital P. City City comes next. City. City City is The City. I imagine your Curtain folks would see this as The City City, too. A City where City happens. A City where tomorrow is Tuesday, and today? It's Monday City. City is a verb in City City, but City, in City City? City is a noun, too. You're City. I'm City. Welcome to City.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:10:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-27-my-favorite-porn-art/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-27-my-favorite-porn-art/</link><title></title><description>My favorite porn artist on here got banned. Idk what for, must have been bad enough to not just remove a post but explode the whole page. I’m not gonna tag them, ask me irl if you want to know, and I’m not looking to shit talk @staff, i trust their judgment.I’m just sad.The tagging system and their asks and multiple years of backlog was nice. Looking at their mastodon is hell comparatively.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 13:58:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-27-legal-meth/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-27-legal-meth/</link><title>Legal meth</title><description>It’s weird to use adderall/vyvanse/mixed methamphetamine salts and see immediate results. I’ve been without my drugs for a month due to the shortage but found my stash of old prescription that was too high, and decided to start taking it because I really like being productive.Turns out, when I take medication, I’m really fucking productive! That’s annoying! Why can’t I just be productive like this normally?Anyway, I stayed up until nearly 1 am last night working on jnet so at least it wasn’t purely for my job’s benefit.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 13:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-25-bongripper-satan/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-25-bongripper-satan/</link><title>bongripper - satan</title><description>https://bongripper.bandcamp.com/track/satan-3that little black sabbath turn at 9:30 cracks me up every time. goes from a glorious piece of repetitive doom to ~we're groovin~. whole album fucks, if you haven't heard it before.</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 20:38:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-25-ruminations-on-techn/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-25-ruminations-on-techn/</link><title>Ruminations on technical debt in jnet (sent from my iPhone)</title><description>&lt;jinteki.net> has a lot of problems, some which are easy to solve and some which are not. There’s a difference between bugs and tech debt. Bugs are things like “misplaced parameters”, or “forgot to check an additional predicate”. Technical debt is “the core system is built on callbacks” or “there is no game loop”.I had a wonderful conversation with someone who is attempting to implement the Netrunner rules as strictly as possible. (She’s gone so far as to implement Netrunner’s R&amp;D location system instead of using a simple vector!) In our many back and forths, I am confident she learned nothing from me lol but I learned a lot from her, both about Netrunner and about how to structure a game engine for Netrunner.jinteki.net is not a good game engine. It works, in part due to the incredible amount of work we’ve all put in over the years, but (to be slightly rude) it has no right to work as well as it should. It’s full of cludges, ad-hoc systems, layers of ideas half implemented on top of each other like dirt strata.</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 01:36:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-24-palisade-41-is-reall/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-24-palisade-41-is-reall/</link><title></title><description>Palisade 41 is really good</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 12:20:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-23-my-review-of-dune-2/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-23-my-review-of-dune-2/</link><title>My review of DUNE 2</title><description>Of all the changes, this was the most disappointing, even more than the removal of Alia.</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 15:41:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-23-me-internally-to-m/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-23-me-internally-to-m/</link><title></title><description>Me (internally) to my kid when she does something so infuriating I feel like my head is going to explode: hell yeah, parents are cops, APAB</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 14:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-21-how-do-you-be-a-good/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-21-how-do-you-be-a-good/</link><title>how do you be a good parent to a kid with a touch of the 'tism when you also have a touch of the 'tism</title><description>i'm not doing a good job and we can't see an occupational therapist until july.my 4 year old probably has sensory processing disorder and adhd, she's self-confident and precocious but lacking in any real world experiences, and she triggers me nearly every day like i'm living at home with my dad. (that's another story for another day.)</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 14:11:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-21-i-need-2-mello-to-re/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-21-i-need-2-mello-to-re/</link><title></title><description>i need 2 mello to release a 10 min version of the second half of biollante</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 13:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-20-the-perfect-celeste/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-20-the-perfect-celeste/</link><title>The Perfect Celeste Run</title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=niuCpSOX_jIi generally only go to the subscriptions page of youtube, but sometimes the front page recommendations hit.This run includes:
All Strawberries (red berries); All Hearts; All Tapes; All Full Clears; All A sides; All B sides; All C sides; Farewell; the Moon Berry; Pico-8 Celeste Classic Full Clear; the Winged Golden Berry; and All Golden Berries, so I had to do every level TWICE.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 20:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-20-pain-at-work-today/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-20-pain-at-work-today/</link><title>pain at work today</title><description>i try to merge to main, the test run on merge fails. i look at the failed test. it's from early 2022, it's 450 lines long, and it starts with defining 20 atoms (mutable variables) in a top-level let block.forget who wrote this, i'm mad about whoever approved this.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 20:42:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-20-occult-ft-tv-ma-b/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-20-occult-ft-tv-ma-b/</link><title>Occult (ft. TV-MA) by 2 Mello and MILLION SUNDAY</title><description>https://2mellomakes.bandcamp.com/track/occult-ft-tv-mathis shit is goes hard and is funny as hell. perfect combo</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 17:44:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-20-djot/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-20-djot/</link><title>djot</title><description>y'all ever heard of djot? It's another markdown alternative, "a lightweight markup language" that's designed to be easier to parse (by computers). It's pretty nifty and I like the look of it. Makes me want to write a clojure parser for it.The inline attributes are specifically very cool. Feels like inline css but for markdown instead of hiding html within your markdown.Given:</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 02:20:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-dinner-time/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-dinner-time/</link><title>Dinner time</title><description></description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 23:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-i-think-a-lot-about/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-i-think-a-lot-about/</link><title></title><description>I think a lot about that conversation at the dinner party near the start of Cryptonomicon by Neal Stephenson where the stuffy academic is like “We have the information superhighway, but what about the information ghettos that lay beneath?” and Randy is like, “you’re so fucking dumb, that’s not how the internet works” and yet 25 years later it’s exactly how the internet works.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 17:27:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-current-playlist-al/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-current-playlist-al/</link><title>current playlist: all monolord songs on shuffle</title><description>https://monolord.bandcamp.com/track/died-a-million-timesmore favorites below the fold</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 16:13:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-me-after-eating-my/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-me-after-eating-my/</link><title></title><description>me, after eating my own breakfast, the leftovers of both of my kids, a brownie, a whole cup of coffee, and a full mason jar of goldfish crackers: yeah, i'm just not really hungry for lunch right now</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 15:57:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-jinteki-net-has-full/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-19-jinteki-net-has-full/</link><title>jinteki.net has full implementation of Rebellion Without Rehearsal</title><description>Full release notes:and while it says "RWR patch by nbkelly", this was a joint effort between nbkelly, Francesco Pellegrini, and butzopower. nbkelly has kept the playtest server updated as NSG developed the set, and buztopower and francesco did a lot of QA and engine work and test writing to ensure things are as good as they can be today. they're all champions and i'm very proud of them/glad for them to pick up the torch since I no longer have time to work on jnet.</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 02:10:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-18-on-our-way-to-target/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-18-on-our-way-to-target/</link><title></title><description>On our way to target
Me: i miss community spaces.
My wife : you don’t think target is a community spa- hahaha</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 21:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-17-may-thy-knife-chip-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-17-may-thy-knife-chip-a/</link><title></title><description>May thy knife chip and shatter, dickwad</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 21:34:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-17-cw-dune-spoilers/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-17-cw-dune-spoilers/</link><title></title><description>I cannot fucking way to see St. Alia of the Knife onscreen. I’m literally vibrating in excitement.</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 19:50:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-17-do-you-think-brian-h/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-17-do-you-think-brian-h/</link><title></title><description>Do you think Brian Herbert was inspired by Princess Irulan to write knock off books?</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 19:36:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-17-reread-the-second-ha/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-17-reread-the-second-ha/</link><title>Reread the second half of Dune in preparation to see DUNC 2 in theaters</title><description>This book is fucking sick and it’s honestly disappointing to see how little of the machinations and politicking of included in the movies. We’ll see how much that changes in D2 but DUNC felt like the barest smatterings of dialogue and context so we could have some beautiful visuals.Which is like fine? But it means that all of the characters are flat, cardboard cutouts of their book selves, that’s basically no compelling reason to care what happens to anyone. My wife, who’s never read the books or seen previous adaptions said, “I can’t pick a favorite character because I don’t know any I’d these characters. Even Paul has no personality, no texture. The movie was one long fight that felt like a prologue to the second film.” I couldn’t disagree with that assessment.</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 19:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-16-new-kacey-musgraves/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-16-new-kacey-musgraves/</link><title>New Kacey Musgraves album is great</title><description>Very mellow, lightly country, kind of poignant, some songs about endings and lost love but not newly divorced energy like last one.</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 20:27:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-15-the-main-goal-of-th/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-15-the-main-goal-of-th/</link><title>"The main goal of this project was to create a sequence of inputs that beats [Pokemon FireRed] with an 100% chance of success."</title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6gjsAA_5Agki love when someone spends a year to do something insane.</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 20:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-15-more-reign-2e-though/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-15-more-reign-2e-though/</link><title>more reign 2e thoughts: there's no gm chapter</title><description>okay, so i just skimmed the rules book again and there's no GM chapter. i glanced through the realms book and there's no GM chapter there either. There's a chapter with 3 example scenarios, but no thoughts or ideas about how to run a game, no "enemies and adversaries", no "how to build a campaign", no "gm principles", no agenda, no vibes, nothing.i know it's from a different era (first edition published in 2008), but i'm really surprised that 2e doesn't include anything. even the ampersand game does this! they've got whole books dedicated to it (varying quality, depending on the edition).i'll be honest, this has tempered my enthusiasm quite a bit.</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 15:20:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-15-https-www-youtube/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-15-https-www-youtube/</link><title></title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dDVDi4avnwkin case you didn't know, vanessa carlton (of "a thousand miles" fame) has continued to release music. her fifth album "Love Is An Art" contains "Companion Star", this beautiful brooding meditation on growth and staying grounded. in the bridge, she repeats "who i want to become, and to whom i always will belong" set to a deep organ. it's my favorite part of the song, a distillation of the whole. i find it satisfying and contemplative, like being wrapped in a warm blanket in the dead of winter.i played it for my wife back when it came out, describing these feelings to her, and she said that the whole song and specifically the bridge left her feeling anxious and sad. wild how different people can experience music.</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 14:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-14-hot-take-spellcheck/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-14-hot-take-spellcheck/</link><title>hot take: spellcheck is bad</title><description>i tried to use the word "immiserate" earlier and firefox's spellchecker yelled at me. this is not a technical or archaic word. and yet it doesn't appear in the "top x words" dictionary that's included by default in firefox.my iphone knows the word, notion doesn't know the word, google docs knows it, neovim doesn't know it.why are we reliant on these things to tell us which words are "real"? shit's dumb. there will be people out there who read or hear a word and think "that's a word" and then go to use it in one of these apps, and it will chastise them, saying "that's not a real word". unless they have the temerity to check a real dictionary, they'll just go "i guess i was wrong" and now their chosen speech is worse and the world is less textured than it was before.</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 14:36:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-14-love-is-blind-season/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-14-love-is-blind-season/</link><title>Love is Blind season 6 reunion</title><description>This shit is raw. The Jeramy-Sarah Ann-Laura fight was revealing of how awful those people are, each of them.The Clay-A.D. conversation is heartbreaking. I’ve loved Clay the whole show, watching him grow and learn and it hurt to see him say no. So hearing him get choked up and speak about how he regrets saying no and his work to get better hit me hard.</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 02:56:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-13-cw-album-art-is-gor/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-13-cw-album-art-is-gor/</link><title></title><description>https://pestcontroluk.bandcamp.com/track/judgement-time</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 19:04:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-13-more-reign-2e-though/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-13-more-reign-2e-though/</link><title>more reign 2e thoughts</title><description>I read some of the Reigns setting book and i forgot how fun and weird it is, but this shit is laid out like ass. There’s no “brief overview of the world and peoples”, it’s just immediately multi-page chapters about each nation state, very little by way of “here’s where they are in relation to each other geographically” or “here’s a historical overview”.Like opening a book titled “United States of America” and it opens with a mapless description of Alabama, then the next chapter is about Wisconsin, followed by New Hampshire. What the hell.</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 14:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-13-i-hope-i-never-forge/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-13-i-hope-i-never-forge/</link><title></title><description>I hope I never forget laying in bed after a long day, seeing that @jdq had released the theme song for Palisade, putting it on, and feeling swept away overcome completely immersed in the poignancy and delicate tension. I knew then that the season was going to be something special, even after so many bangers, and every single episode has met that high mark.</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 02:18:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-12-reign-2e/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-12-reign-2e/</link><title>Reign 2e</title><description>I got my copy of Reign 2e and Reign: Realms. I read through the core book, will read Realms tomorrow. Gonna copy my thoughts from pms I sent my friend:Okay, i read it. I skipped the details on the advanced combat and the minutiae of the advantages/powers/magic, but read all the core rules and the company stuff.It’s the most traditional game I’ve read in a long time. It’s fun! I love the ORE, i don’t like binary dice mechanics, i love love love Greg Stolze’s writing voice, i like that the text spends some time to say “gm, don’t just run players through a plot” and “players, don’t just sit around waiting for plot to fall from heaven”. I like that a whole chapter is a “table of contents” of the various subsystems, explicitly saying “choose only the roles you want to make the kind of game you want, please don’t pick everything”</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 05:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-11-yuki-s-vacation-an/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-11-yuki-s-vacation-an/</link><title>"Yuki's Vacation" and a call for help from chinese speakers</title><description>There's an abandoned freeware game made by James Silva (Ska Studios, The Dishwasher, Salt and Sanctuary) in 2002 called Yuki's Vacation. He made it in Visual Basic 6 after Zombie Smasher X as a way of showing how he made games. I was already obsessed with Zombie Smasher X (just look at this gloriousness), so getting access to the source code was a revelation.I spent hours playing around with it, editing the bmps, changing the level design, doing really basic programming (I didn't really know what I was doing) back in 2002 and 2003. It was foundational for me seeing programming as something I could do and not just "magic by people smarter than me".Every so often, I search for the code online and can't find it (because who the hell would keep freeware visual basic code for 20+ years), but I think I've come across it here. The site is in Chinese and even with Google Translate, I can't get the system to allow me to create an account so I can download this. I hope it doesn't cost money to download, but I'm willing to pay $20 if you can help me out here. It's really meaningful to me.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 16:51:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-10-if-daylight-saving-t/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-10-if-daylight-saving-t/</link><title></title><description>If Daylight Saving Time has million haters, then I'm one of them.
If Daylight Saving Time has one hater, then that’s me.
If Daylight Saving Time has no haters, then I’m dead.
If the world is for Daylight Saving Time, then I am against the world.
Till my last breath, I’ll hate Daylight Saving Time.</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 11:23:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-10-i-wanna-make-a-websi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-10-i-wanna-make-a-websi/</link><title>i wanna make a website</title><description>i have a github pages site but i would prefer to self host. buying a domain is the easy part. what do i do after that? what if i want to set up a plex-like home media server that’s i can access when away from the house?</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 01:22:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-09-when-taylor-sings-b/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-09-when-taylor-sings-b/</link><title></title><description>When Taylor sings “boys and boys” in welcome to New York, it sounds like she’s gonna say “boysenberries”</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 16:56:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-08-i-love-that-doublef/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-08-i-love-that-doublef/</link><title></title><description>i love that @doublefine is a real account and @todd-howard is also a real account. both are real accounts tied to the real people they're named for. cohost is truly unique in that regard.</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 21:16:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-08-buying-digital-music/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-08-buying-digital-music/</link><title>buying digital music</title><description>i buy almost all of my music through bandcamp, but there are a lot of artists (mostly those signed with big name labels) that don't have their music on it. for the other music i want, i have to use qobuz.qobuz, for those who don't know, is a streaming service and digital music store that sells FLAC/etc versions of music from big labels. It's quite comprehensive and boasts the best per-track streaming payout for artists ($0.04 per track listened).Alongside that, it's significantly more expensive than bandcamp. For example, At the Walls by Enforced is $8 on Bandcamp. Kill Grid (released by Century Media) is $15 for mp3, $18 for FLAC. (I know that At the Walls is cheaper on Qobuz, I'm talking about big label releases rn.)</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 15:41:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-07-name-ideas/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-07-name-ideas/</link><title>Name ideas</title><description>Fidget
Lakeside
Barrier
Conifer
Silicone
Harken
Methodical
Presently</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:28:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-07-i-was-install-a-coup/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-07-i-was-install-a-coup/</link><title></title><description>I was install a couple QoL mods for dragon’s dogma on my Steam deck, but every tutorial sucks. Anyone have a good tutorial on hand for this?</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 04:03:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-05-me-every-time-i-see/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-05-me-every-time-i-see/</link><title></title><description>Me every time i see an Over the Garden Wall mention: huh, dreamworld animation still has fans? Good for them and good for Ben Folds.</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:03:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-05-eggs-bene-gesserit/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-05-eggs-bene-gesserit/</link><title></title><description>eggs bene gesserit</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 16:51:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-05-what-is-this-data-st/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-05-what-is-this-data-st/</link><title>What is this data structure?</title><description>I re-discovered a data structure I used many years ago from a game engine. It’s like a queue but is well built for recursive or nested work. The name I know it as is the Pipeline.The data structure is { processed: queue, added: queue }. It has the methods enqueue(…args: any[]): pipeline, peek(): any, and pop(): pipeline.When you call enqueue, you pass in any number of items, which are added to the back of the added internal queue. Like a classic queue, if enqueue is called multiple times in a row, each set of items is added at the end.</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 04:41:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-05-the-volcano-is-death/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-05-the-volcano-is-death/</link><title></title><description>The volcano is death, the lava is death
Death is life, the lava is life
The volcano is death, the lava is death
Death is life, the lava is life
The volcano is death, the lava is death
Death is life, the lava is life
The volcano is death, the lava is death
Death is life, the lava is life</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:02:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-04-just-pushed-my-4-yea/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-04-just-pushed-my-4-yea/</link><title></title><description>Just pushed my 4 year old off the swing. AMA</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 23:17:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-04-every-day-i-get-wors/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-04-every-day-i-get-wors/</link><title>every day i get worse at Really Bad Chess</title><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 16:55:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-04-god-kant-was-so-aut/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-04-god-kant-was-so-aut/</link><title></title><description>god, kant was so autistic</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 15:50:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-04-you-ever-start-shred/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-04-you-ever-start-shred/</link><title></title><description>You ever start shredding cheese for some small portion and then kind of zone out in the simple pleasure of the movement and watching the block in your hand shrink and then you snap to to see the cheese practically poking out of the top of the shredder?Me either</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 13:56:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-03-to-be-a-pedant/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-03-to-be-a-pedant/</link><title>To be a pedant</title><description>I hate that “dad joke” has become a cultural thing, specifically being used to refer to puns. Puns are great, but dad jokes as I understood them are about deliberate misunderstandings for comedic effect. They can use puns to find or create the misunderstanding, but the fun comes from the parallel conversation and the moment of realization.</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 21:37:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-03-shit-has-fully-poppe/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-03-shit-has-fully-poppe/</link><title>Shit has fully popped off</title><description></description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 16:38:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-02-yeeesssssssss/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-02-yeeesssssssss/</link><title>YEEESSSSSSSSS</title><description></description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 03:50:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-02-pregante/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-03-02-pregante/</link><title>Preganté</title><description>Did some big cummies!!!!!!!!!!!</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:26:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-28-broke-god-she-s-so/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-28-broke-god-she-s-so/</link><title></title><description>Broke: God, she’s so fucking hot Woke: mother is mothering</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 13:57:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-28-new-inter-arma-is-on/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-28-new-inter-arma-is-on/</link><title>New Inter Arma is one of the best in their oeuvre</title><description>https://interarma.bandcamp.com/track/new-heaven</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 04:40:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-27-been-playing-control/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-27-been-playing-control/</link><title></title><description>Been playing Control on my steam deck. This game fucks. Amazing atmosphere of dread and anxiety without ever getting too scary for me. I’m dumped all of my ability points into telekinesis, because it’s satisfying. Nothing beats it yet except those flying turds.Idk what’s going on, i barely understand the story, there’s a lot of mystery and very little explanation and I’m just along for the ride, really.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 04:01:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-26-you-know-what-s-grea/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-26-you-know-what-s-grea/</link><title></title><description>You know what’s great? Deciding to catch up on a year of a podcast and adding 67 hours of episodes to my existing 10 hours of podcasts in my listening queue.“What podcast?” I stopped listening to A More Civilized Age when they started Rebels cuz I didn’t have time to watch but wanted to follow along. I’ve watched the whole first season now and I’m ready lol</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 12:39:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-26-we-re-2-episodes-fro/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-26-we-re-2-episodes-fro/</link><title></title><description>We’re 2 episodes from the end of season 15 of rupaul’s drag race, and May’s paramount + preview ended. We signed in with our friend’s account that does ads, and the very first ad we saw was an MTV commercial “celebrating the winner of RuPaul’s Drag Race season 15”</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 03:08:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-25-learned-about-the-ta/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-25-learned-about-the-ta/</link><title></title><description>Learned about the takeover of da share z0ne yesterday, like a lot of terminally online folks. Pretty disappointing and disheartening.I had assumed that, like dril, this was the work of one person who had changed over time. Tastes change, writing voice changes, goals change, so it makes sense that the quality would shift. Not every dril tweet is a banger, not every da share zone is either.But learning that the quality drop comes from a coup by a money grubbing asshole who is only mimicking the better work of the people he stole the account from really fucking sucks. Can’t escape the clutches of greed or money anywhere.</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 16:02:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-25-she-s-on-fire-with-t/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-25-she-s-on-fire-with-t/</link><title></title><description>She’s on fire with these fuckin mashups, my god.</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 13:33:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-24-you-re-telling-me-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-24-you-re-telling-me-a/</link><title></title><description>You’re telling me a duck came on these feet?</description><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 13:31:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-22-i-want-to-build-a-ho/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-22-i-want-to-build-a-ho/</link><title></title><description>I want to build a home server/NAS so i can have a central place for my digital music and run some small web apps. Anyone have suggestions? I have 3/4 of a desktop in parts in my closet, but I’m also not against just buying a prebuilt thing if anyone has strong feelings</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 13:19:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-22-got-a-new-m3-mac-book/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-22-got-a-new-m3-mac-book/</link><title></title><description>Got a new M3 MacBook Pro to replace my Dell Ubuntu machine at my job. The Ubuntu machine was a little janky but rock solid, a powerhouse for the backend webdev work I do. The mbp is a locked down nightmare, covered in corporate malware. I have root, but I’m not allowed to install “non approved software” or “use external storage devices” and they’ll know if I disable anything.Most importantly, they haven’t granted approval for Karabiner-Elements, so I might lose out on my custom layout I’ve been using for 8 years.The M3 processor is nice but idk that it’s worth all this shit.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 04:19:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-21-you-know-dead-flag/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-21-you-know-dead-flag/</link><title></title><description>you know "dead flag blues" by godspeed you black emperor? there's that line "the sun has fallen down" and i always think "and the moon has come up, and long ago somebody left with the cup"like granny weatherall, i'm going to be on my deathbed, surrounded by friends and family, and all i'll be able to think is, "he's going the distance!"</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 15:42:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-21-what-it-feels-like-t/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-21-what-it-feels-like-t/</link><title>What it feels like to say “we’re trying for a baby”</title><description></description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 05:53:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-21-damn-story-games-cl/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-21-damn-story-games-cl/</link><title></title><description>damn, story-games closed? and all the links are now broken??? :eggbug-sob:</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 03:56:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-21-nothing-more-annoyin/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-21-nothing-more-annoyin/</link><title>nothing more annoying that thinking of a clever optimization, implementing it, and the benchmarks don't change</title><description>what is even the point of thinking about this stuff if it doesn't work :eggbug-sob:</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 03:52:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-20-https-www-rascal-n/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-20-https-www-rascal-n/</link><title></title><description>https://www.rascal.news/rascal-domain-expansion-alternative-independent-roguelike/I’m fuckin pumped. Subscribed-funded! Worker owned! Tabletop Roleplaying Games journalism! By some real bad asses!</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 22:51:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-20-splint-updates-oops/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-20-splint-updates-oops/</link><title>Splint updates! Oops it's been 8 months edition</title><description>I forgot to post about the updates back in December, so I'm gonna write about everything from 1.11 through 1.14.The biggest changes since last summer are a global top-level entry in .splint.edn that applies to all files, supporting the upcoming Clojure 1.12 interop syntax ((^[] String/toUpperCase "noah")), and simplifying the internal logic of the pattern DSL so that the short forms are expanded to their full forms before processing.Paired with the global entry in .splint.edn, I implemented :excludes, which will skip specified files or directories in global or in specific rules. The paths can be specified with Java's java.nio.file.FileSystem/getPathMatcher globs or regexes, as well as :re-find and :string. Details here.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 17:18:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-20-the-only-bullet-hell/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-20-the-only-bullet-hell/</link><title></title><description>The only bullet hell I play is SNAKE FARM</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 04:02:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-20-l-my-4-year-old-dau/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-20-l-my-4-year-old-dau/</link><title></title><description>L, my 4 year old daughter: I know an old lady who actually ACTUALLY swallowed a thumb!Then she chomped on my thumb.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:42:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-15-cw-kanye-west-and-h/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-15-cw-kanye-west-and-h/</link><title></title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M0jEngxUFz4i've never been the biggest fan of fantano, his reviews are mostly just kind of boring, but this is something else. an excoriation of the kanye fanbase, calling them out for their devotion to kanye and their steadfast refusal to meaningfully interact with his increasingly unhinged, misogynist, anti-semetic behavior. i've pulled some quotes (lightly edited for reading clarity) from the review in the "read more" if you don't want to watch it.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 15:44:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-13-https-twitter-com/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-13-https-twitter-com/</link><title></title><description>https://twitter.com/pronounced_kyle/status/1757215139550605713So GitLab posts their internal Zoom call recordings on YouTube, and some have HUNDREDS OF THOUSANDS of views...Because people use them to pretend like they're working.Includes two pictures, one of youtube comments in thanks, and one of the youtube video</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:31:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-12-congrats-to-taylor-s/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-12-congrats-to-taylor-s/</link><title></title><description>Congrats to Taylor Swift on winning the Super Bowl</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 03:57:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-12-may-made-this-cookie/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-12-may-made-this-cookie/</link><title></title><description>May made this cookie cake from scratch.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:13:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-11-viscerally-annoyed/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-11-viscerally-annoyed/</link><title>Viscerally annoyed</title><description>I’m trying to learn Ocaml. It’s going okay, learning new languages is hard, and learning new warts is the hardest part. I came across one that’s left me so viscerally annoyed that I might stop learning the language altogether.I’m struggling to write a real post about this lol. I keep deleting my words.I’m annoyed that argument order evaluation is deliberately unspecified in the language spec and the primary compiler evaluates arguments right to left.</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 20:51:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-11-at-dinner-with-my-wi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-11-at-dinner-with-my-wi/</link><title>At dinner with my wife</title><description>Me: why is the menu all Italian words? I thought it was Mediterranean. … i guess Italy is surrounded on all sides by the Mediterranean Sea… “I’m getting Mediterranean tonight, ordering some papa John’s.”</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 01:38:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-10-https-www-youtube/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-10-https-www-youtube/</link><title></title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AfSjnsYiY_Aexcuse me i'm obsessed</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 04:28:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-08-https-x-com-badcop/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-08-https-x-com-badcop/</link><title></title><description>https://x.com/badcop_/status/1755380428377043426</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:30:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-05-award-shows-are-dumb/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-05-award-shows-are-dumb/</link><title></title><description>award shows are dumb but seeing annie lennox say "artists for ceasefire, peace in the world" and then get cut off was pretty sick.https://twitter.com/Variety/status/1754336387007156352</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 02:57:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-05-just-popped-into-my/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-05-just-popped-into-my/</link><title></title><description>just popped into my head the time someone complained to me about their issues with PbtA games being that 2d6+stat makes the bell curve too hard to calculate. i'm trying to remember their argument, but they were annoyed that one of the jumps is like 22% difference, and then the next jump was like 15 or 17% or something. i asked if they didn't play pbta because of it and they were like "no, my group just figured out a better curve with d10s and house rule all pbta games to use it instead." i asked if they knew about the Spire and "sparked by resistence" games, and he was like "we're happy with pbta."nerds are very silly what they get hung up on.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 01:27:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-04-my-wife-about-a-gro/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-02-04-my-wife-about-a-gro/</link><title></title><description>My wife, about a gross dude on tv: ew, no man, you’re 37, you’re old.
Me: you know, I’m about to turn 37.
Her: there are some thoughts and feelings related to age I need to reconsider</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 04:01:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-30-lost-in-cult-immor/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-30-lost-in-cult-immor/</link><title></title><description>Lost In Cult: Immortalitythis is so beautiful, i could weep. i bought the fancy book. was expensive :eggbug-nervous: but i cannot wait to read through it.as much as i wanted the posters, i couldn't bring myself to get the big box. it's so much more expensive and i don't need the soundtracks or the ticket stubs or the separate scripts.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 14:33:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-28-ocaml-popularity/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-28-ocaml-popularity/</link><title>Ocaml Popularity</title><description>Because I’m terminally online, I had this impression that Ocaml was fairly popular, the younger cousin of Haskell. But it seems to be relatively unknown? Barely any talks on YouTube (the 5+ years of Ocaml workshops aren’t online, which is insane to me), fairly slow traffic on the subreddit and forums, not super active discord server, etc.I’m still glad to learn it and I’m enjoying it a lot, just surprising to learn.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 23:55:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-25-https-www-theverge/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-25-https-www-theverge/</link><title></title><description>https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/25/24049050/microsoft-activision-blizzard-layoffsi fuckin hate these ghouls. to loosely quote ebenezer scrooge, "If I could work my will, every idiot who goes about with 'you're fired' on his lips, should be boiled with his own pudding, and buried with a stake of holly through his heart."</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 15:27:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-24-https-www-youtube/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-24-https-www-youtube/</link><title></title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kmpyfDF_pesdamn. nothing's ever gonna hit as hard as strange desire but i hold out hope, and this is quite the spark.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 21:21:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-24-this-is-us/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-24-this-is-us/</link><title>This Is Us</title><description>I’ve been watching This Is Us with my wife, we’re halfway through season 1, and it’s a fine, pleasant show. Lots of well done moments about family and parenthood and generational trauma.However, they also have moments of these characters just cratering their lives instead of doing literally anything else, and it sucks all the fun out of the show. I finally had to leave the room when Kevin literally left his costar on stage opening night of their play, just ran out of the building. The music swelled, the moment was textured with him saying, “I’m thinking about what my dad would do”, showing how meaningful this is/supposed to be. But that shit ain’t cool! Embarrassing yourself is one thing. Humiliating your costar with no explanation is unconscionable.Earlier in the episode, I had to leave the room cuz another moment was also rough and my wife said, “Can you not watch the show at a remove?” No, I cannot. All media I consume I consume fully. To hear a story is to embody the story in my head and in my heart. It’s nice when I’m crying to Joanna Newsom while washing dishes, but it’s annoying when i just want to enjoy some saccharine feel-good drama.</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 03:12:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-22-i-want-a-tattoo-that/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-22-i-want-a-tattoo-that/</link><title>I want a tattoo that communicates the same vibe as putting a rainbow flag in my home’s living window.</title><description>I know that such signals aren’t perfect, that bad people also get pride tattoos, that there’s no way to say “I’m safe” unless someone actually interacts with me and makes that value judgment themselves.</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 23:15:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-22-me-all-metal-and-me/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-22-me-all-metal-and-me/</link><title></title><description>me: all metal and metal-adjacent is real metal, metal nerds are bad, and exclusionary politics are bad
also me: sleep token is the worst thing to have ever happened to metal</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 20:24:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-22-cohost-is-the-best-w/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-22-cohost-is-the-best-w/</link><title>cohost is the best website</title><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 14:40:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2024-01-19-gender-feelings/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2024-01-19-gender-feelings/</link><title>gender feelings</title><description>i wrote this post last week but i actually came up with the joke back in the fall. i've been mulling it over ever since, and i think i know why it resonates. this might take a moment to write out tho, so my apologies up front.i will start at the end.after much introspection, i am not trans. i feel great in my body, i like being seen as a man and by all accounts i experience gender euphoria, i like being "papa" to my kids "husband" to my wife and "son" to my parents, i like my birth name.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 17:08:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-19-i-m-at-the-final-sec/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-19-i-m-at-the-final-sec/</link><title></title><description>I’m at the final section of Guacamelee and this game is charming as hell. 2/2 from DrinkBox, tho Severed was significantly better.I can’t wait to finish the main game and then 100% it. A perfect length for a game, imp.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 06:57:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-17-details-summary-t/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-17-details-summary-t/</link><title></title><description></description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 20:34:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-16-song-of-the-day/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-16-song-of-the-day/</link><title>song of the day</title><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i2r0XtgB7gw</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 14:49:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-16-if-you-publish-a-boo/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-16-if-you-publish-a-boo/</link><title></title><description>If you publish a book of sheet music for music played on the piano that includes both piano and vocal lines, and then make the right hand of the piano mirror the vocal lines instead of match the actual played piano part,I hope you get hit by a fucking bus and are unable to work in the sheet music industry for the rest of your life.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:48:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-14-watching-tv-with-a-2/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-14-watching-tv-with-a-2/</link><title>Watching tv with a 2 year old</title><description></description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 17:34:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-14-trans-jerry-i-have/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-14-trans-jerry-i-have/</link><title></title><description>Trans Jerry: I have a suspicion that she’s transitioned just for the jokes.Father: And this offends you as a trans person.Trans Jerry: No, it offends me as a comedian!</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 17:29:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2024-01-14-trans-jerry/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2024-01-14-trans-jerry/</link><title>seinfeld joke</title><description>Trans Jerry: I have a suspicion that she’s transitioned just for the jokes.Father: And this offends you as a trans person.Trans Jerry: No, it offends me as a comedian!</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 12:29:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-13-my-wife-may-you-kid/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-13-my-wife-may-you-kid/</link><title></title><description>My wife May: You kids want yogurt and granola?
My 4 year old,, yelling indignantly: I want a bowl of frozen corn!</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 13:37:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-12-dasharez0ne-doesn-t/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-12-dasharez0ne-doesn-t/</link><title></title><description>@dasharez0ne doesn't post all their memes, so i must share this onebuy skelaton shit at HTTPS://DASHARE.ZONE</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 16:22:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-11-7-years-together-and/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-11-7-years-together-and/</link><title>7 years together and 5 years married</title><description>fun fact: our first date, the day i proposed, and the day we got married fall on the same day, jan 11th, each a year apart. makes counting and planning really easy, i highly recommend it.this photo is in the rhinegeist brewery stairwell where we had our first kiss and then a year later where we got married.</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 16:40:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-05-tyranny-of-the-blank/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-05-tyranny-of-the-blank/</link><title>tyranny of the blank page</title><description>i spent multiple days thinking about a way to approach a technical problem, and decided that starting fresh was the right way to go. i gen'd a new project directory, opened the main file, and then sat and puzzled like the grinch for 3 hours until my puzzler was sore and it was time for bed with nearly nothing written.maybe some of those thoughts will be helpful in the future, but dang it's annoying to make no visible progress.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 14:50:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-02-what-the-fuck-is-up/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-02-what-the-fuck-is-up/</link><title>what the fuck is up with passkeys</title><description>From GitHub:Passkeys are a password replacement that validates your identity using touch, facial recognition, a device password, or a PIN.How is a PIN any better than a password? There's mathematically no way for a 4-10 digit number to have greater entropy than my 73 character full-keyboard password.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 15:20:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-02-pirating-music-when/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-02-pirating-music-when/</link><title></title><description>Pirating music when the artist/band has a bandcamp: feels very bad, i don’t do this
Pirating music when the artist is only on qobuz: feel less bad but still avoid in general
Pirating music that i have at one time purchased: feels great
Pirating music for bands my mom had heard of: feels great too, means they made it</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 05:58:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-02-got-a-new-tattoo-ove/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-02-got-a-new-tattoo-ove/</link><title>Got a new tattoo over the holiday</title><description>The Snowy Day is my favorite children’s book and I’ve wanted to get this since I first read it to my daughter. I think it’s great.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:17:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-01-1-death-stranding-2/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-01-1-death-stranding-2/</link><title></title><description>![](/img/cohost-mirror/4039109-1-death-stranding-2/chart 2.png)</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 02:02:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-01-empty/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2024-01-01-empty/</link><title></title><description></description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 01:42:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-31-everyone-i-know-post/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-31-everyone-i-know-post/</link><title></title><description>Everyone I know posted their Spotify Wrapped at the beginning of December. I went a different route and calculated my top 25 albums this year by time spent listening, multiplying scrobbled tracks by their length and grouping by album. (Full list below the fold)</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 06:15:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-31-may-hands-me-a-fancy/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-31-may-hands-me-a-fancy/</link><title></title><description>May hands me a fancy grape: Here, taste this.
Me, who just ate all of the kids left over refried beans: Getting a lot of bean from these grapes.</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:50:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-27-iv-gha-h-ba-hw-i-e/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-27-iv-gha-h-ba-hw-i-e/</link><title>'Iv ghaH baHwI''e'</title><description>"Who's on first?", performed in the original Klingon (tlhIngan Hol).Text of the recording is from jatmey volume 4, unavailable for purchase here.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 04:11:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-26-the-existence-of-per/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-26-the-existence-of-per/</link><title></title><description>The existence of perishable food is proof that god exists and doesn’t like us much</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 19:28:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-26-my-3-11-year-old-ope/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-26-my-3-11-year-old-ope/</link><title></title><description>My 3.11 year old opens the door to the bathroom while I’m in it, says: papa, whenever you’re done, wheneve-when you’re done with your penis or butt, when you’re done pooping or peeing, or pooping and peeing, papa when you’re done in the bathroom, can you go to the basement and get my baby yoda doll from out of the basement?</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 14:59:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-25-death-stranding-revi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-25-death-stranding-revi/</link><title>Death Stranding Review</title><description>NoahTheDukereviewed Death Stranding: Director's CutCompletedonPlayStation 5The first real mission, you have to carry your deceased mother’s body to an incinerator for cremation. As you leave the compound, the camera pulls back as Low Roar’s Bones plays. Once it ends, you’re left with Sam’s labored breathing and footfalls as the only soundtrack. After delivering the body and lighting the flame, you encounter the otherworldly enemies, the BTs, for the first time in gameplay. The fetus in the glass womb at your chest sobs nonstop until you get away from them.My second kid was born less than a week before I started playing, and my wife’s mom had died unexpectedly 6 months before. I found the entire mission so emotionally trying that I put the game down until the start of the next year.Once I returned, I found a singular experience: meditative, taxing, scary, poignant. I drew a lot of comfort in the effort it took to travel between destinations, relaxing into the mild challenge and allowing my adhd-riddled mind to quiet. The story, on the other hand, repeatedly knocked me on my ass. I cried multiple times, found both pain and solace in the way it handled death and grief and loss. Each of the major characters brought a different aspect of the recovery and healing process to the forefront, and their respective performances were unmatched in games.I take issue with the focus on gun-based violence in the game. It felt great to play, I won’t lie, but it was so discordant with the themes of pain and disconnection and reconnection that I found myself disappointed in its prominence. Especially at the end, with 4 violence-focused bosses in a row, it felt like two games fighting each other for primacy.Accepting that, I think this is a nearly-perfect game, and have spent the rest of the year thinking, “this other game is good, but I should go back to Death Stranding and run some more missions for the preppers.”Reviewed on Dec 25, 2023</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2023 17:18:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-23-me-i-wonder-what-it/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-23-me-i-wonder-what-it/</link><title></title><description>Me: i wonder what its like to enjoy giving and receiving presents
My wife May: you’re an insane person</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 04:14:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-23-new-year-s-resolutio/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-23-new-year-s-resolutio/</link><title></title><description>New Year’s resolution: maybe think about writing a couple sentences about each game I play, finished or not.</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:47:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-22-div-style-display/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-22-div-style-display/</link><title></title><description>NoahTheDukereviewed Cobalt CoreCompletedonWindows PCI’ve beaten the boss twice and each time, I feel like a god.The music is brilliant and the art is cute and the writing is really funny and the conceit feels right for the gameplay.Reviewed on Dec 22, 2023</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 23:52:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-22-my-wife-looks-over-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-22-my-wife-looks-over-a/</link><title></title><description>My wife looks over at me while I’m driving us: you’re aging again, my love.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:52:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-22-my-3-y-o-daughter-h/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-22-my-3-y-o-daughter-h/</link><title></title><description>My 3 y.o. daughter has been experimenting with jokes: “Can I tell you a joke? A building is actually a tree!!”</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 18:47:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-22-liking-darth-vader-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-22-liking-darth-vader-a/</link><title></title><description>Liking Darth Vader and the Empire is equivalent to liking Hitler and The Nazis.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 15:55:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-20-posting-wish-s-musi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-20-posting-wish-s-musi/</link><title></title><description>Posting “Wish’s music is better than Moana’s” just to feel something</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 18:31:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-20-i-don-t-have-the-sou/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-20-i-don-t-have-the-sou/</link><title>i don’t have the soul of a poster</title><description>would be pretty cool if i did</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:44:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-19-galaxies-in-peril/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-19-galaxies-in-peril/</link><title>Galaxies in Peril</title><description>When looking at my bookshelf in the basement, I found a copy of Galaxies in Peril I’d completely forgotten I’d backed on kickstarter. Leafing through it, it looks to be a solid upgrade from Worlds in Peril, which was a mess of a PbtA game lol. (Tho on the other hand, I thought Hack the Planet was supremely bad.)Anyone play it or run it? What did you think?</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 23:26:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-17-floppy-knights-ost-b/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-17-floppy-knights-ost-b/</link><title>Floppy Knights OST by Grahm Nesbitt micro-review</title><description>Perfectly captures the experience of the original Pokémon Red/Blue soundtracks. Catchy, fairly simple, sick solos, every track is memorable. 10/10Game is good too, btw.</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 21:54:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-17-encanto-isn-t-good/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-17-encanto-isn-t-good/</link><title>Encanto isn’t good</title><description>Every time I watch it (sit and view, or spy it while my kids watch it), I’m taken aback by Abuela’s callousness and cruelty and selfishness. In the opening, she’s tender and kind, and then the rest of the movie she’s heartless. And giving her a last minute redemption by way of her sob story (that we already knew! there’s no reveal! the movie opens with it!) washes away all of the pain and hurt she caused.It’s a movie wearing the clothes of “healing generational trauma” that provides a convenient excuse for older generations. According to the movie, all they have to say is, “I was hurting too” and not only is your pain not allowed to exist anymore, but it’s on you to give them comfort and kindness. Alongside that, no one else is responsible for their culpability in allowing this to happen or for how poorly they treated you. (Seriously, fuck Mirabel’s parents. Spineless cowards.)I don’t feel like writing the whole comparison, but Turning Red does a similar story better.</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-15-shameful-local-man/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-15-shameful-local-man/</link><title></title><description>shameful: local man cries during "beauty and the beast (tale as old as time)" when showing it to his daughter for the first time</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 13:21:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-10-bad-news-i-wanna-re/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-10-bad-news-i-wanna-re/</link><title></title><description>bad news: i wanna rebuy all of the indie games i have on switch on my steam deck</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 19:02:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-09-after-nearly-4-years/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-09-after-nearly-4-years/</link><title></title><description>After nearly 4 years, I can safely say that having kids isn’t worth it</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 18:01:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-04-forgot-about-this-dr/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-04-forgot-about-this-dr/</link><title>Forgot about this draft post</title><description>I wrote this draft months ago right before bed, planning on coming back to it in the morning. Now I don’t remember what my breakthrough was. Damn. The description below of jnet’s problems is well worth reading if you give a shit, but never resolves lol.Original post:I’ve had a breakthrough about jinyeki.net’s engine</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 22:55:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-03-steam-deck-thoughts/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-03-steam-deck-thoughts/</link><title>Steam Deck thoughts after an hour</title><description>I impulsively bought a Steam Deck OLED this week and played it for an hour before bed last night.The machine is way nicer than the Switch.</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 16:46:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-03-people-keep-talking/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-12-03-people-keep-talking/</link><title></title><description>People keep talking about how good void stranger is but i never made it past the second group of levels in baba is you. Seems like I’d probably hate it. But people keep saying it’s divine! Harrumph</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 02:57:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-30-here-s-my-top-25-alb/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-30-here-s-my-top-25-alb/</link><title>here's my top 25 albums from the last 365 days</title><description>fuck spotify, so here's my collage from last.fm</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 16:36:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-27-steam-deck-oled/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-27-steam-deck-oled/</link><title>Steam Deck OLED</title><description>I’m buying one for myself for Christmas. Is the 1TB version worth the extra $100? What’s the difference vs buying a cheap 1TB sd card?</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 01:40:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-25-lisa11-fork-yeah/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-25-lisa11-fork-yeah/</link><title>LISA11 - “Fork Yeah! The Rise and Development of illumos” by Bryan Cantrill</title><description>https://youtu.be/-zRN7XLCRhc?t=33m1sDo not fall into the trap of anthropomorphising Larry Ellison. You need to think of Larry Ellison the way you think of a lawnmower. You don't anthropomorphize your lawnmower, the lawnmower just mows the lawn, you stick your hand in there and it'll chop it off, the end. You don't think 'oh, the lawnmower hates me' -- lawnmower doesn't give a shit about you, lawnmower can't hate you. Don't anthropomorphize the lawnmower. Don't fall into that trap about Oracle.</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 17:32:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-24-me-holding-six-book/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-24-me-holding-six-book/</link><title></title><description>Me, holding six books at Half-Price Books
My wife May: that’s a lot of books for someone who doesn’t read books.</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 23:57:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-21-the-funny-thing-abou/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-21-the-funny-thing-abou/</link><title></title><description>the funny thing about chat servers is that they're self-contained communities. to feel comfortable in one, you need to spend enough time to both know the other people and to be known by them. you gotta learn the implications and usages of the emoji, you gotta learn the in-jokes and the history, you gotta actually put in effort to be a real part of the community! you can't skip right to the "i enjoy being here" part.i've been in the netrunner slack server for ~7 years. i only have a handful of channels i'm in, and only some of those that are unmuted. i know the regulars, i know and have created the emojis, i am in it. i only got here because i've been chatting and contributing and reading constantly this whole time. just for my little corner! not even the "whole" server, just the channels I'm active in.joining the discord for some new thing is not exciting, it's daunting and intimidating because that means to actually join and care about the community, i need to be willing to put in the high effort it takes to pay attention and participate. it's not a small task, it in fact might be the biggest task.</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 13:53:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-21-after-subscribing-to/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-21-after-subscribing-to/</link><title>after subscribing to multiple worker-owned media companies and patreons</title><description></description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 13:28:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-20-i-think-garden-is-su/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-20-i-think-garden-is-su/</link><title></title><description>@voidmoth asked:do you have a preferred method for generating/integrating CSS in Clojurescript projects (via Garden, CLJSS, or whatever else) or do you just end up writing CSS normally?I think Garden is super cool, but I am not a frontend kind of person, so I don't have further strong opinions. For jnet, the original dev used Stylus which we have continued to use. I find css in generally pretty hard to read and stylus in particular very hard to read lol (very deep nesting with no brackets???) but it works so it's hard to hate on.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 15:41:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-18-earlier-this-week-i/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-18-earlier-this-week-i/</link><title></title><description>Earlier this week I reached a full year of daily knotwords plays. I’ve missed a fair number in that period, but knotwords generous streak recovery system means that I can actually achieve stuff like this.This was nearly my game of the year last year and a year later, I have no plans or desire to ever stop playing. Every day is a delight.</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 05:43:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-17-thoughts-on-being-po/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-17-thoughts-on-being-po/</link><title>thoughts on being polyamorous</title><description>a friend asked me recently about my "poly" status with my wife, and i started to write a short thing which turned into a long thing. here it is as i sent it to her, to avoid editing and nitpicking it into not getting posted.here's a bunch of pieces that all kind of commingle here, so it's a bit of a mess, but the short version is something like:</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 19:15:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-17-kid-i-want-orzo-mom/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-17-kid-i-want-orzo-mom/</link><title></title><description>Kid: i want orzo
Mom: we have orzo at home
At home: 🍚</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 18:04:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-17-got-to-the-last-batc/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-17-got-to-the-last-batc/</link><title></title><description>got to the last batch of stages in neon white and these might be the best yet. spoilers belowthe book of life cards are sick, amazing mechanic. and then combining that with the various weapons to just go as fast as fucking possible feels insane, like some of the best game feel i've ever experienced from a game.</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 17:08:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-17-i-gotta-use-cohost-m/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-17-i-gotta-use-cohost-m/</link><title></title><description>i gotta use cohost more casually, just write whatever dumb shit comes to mind</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 16:38:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2023-11-17-thoughts-on-being-polyamorous/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2023-11-17-thoughts-on-being-polyamorous/</link><title>thoughts on being polyamorous</title><description>a friend asked me recently about my "poly" status with my wife, and i started to write a short thing which turned into a long thing. here it is as i sent it to her, to avoid editing and nitpicking it into not getting posted.here's a bunch of pieces that all kind of commingle here, so it's a bit of a mess, but the short version is something like:</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 14:15:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-15-saw-a-post-that-upse/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-15-saw-a-post-that-upse/</link><title></title><description>Saw a post that upset me because it was petty and bitchy and pure crab mentality. Spent the afternoon stewing on it and crafting the perfect bitchy reply, and then I remembered I can just block people instead of getting into internet slap fights.Feels like a weight has been lifted from my shoulders.</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 02:09:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-13-me-i-wanna-learn-sp/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-13-me-i-wanna-learn-sp/</link><title></title><description>me: i wanna learn spanish, but i don't want to put in any work so i'm gonna watch/listen to spanish speaking twitch streams
also me: wow i can't understand anything these people are saying</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 13:59:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-11-winter-is-too-cold/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-11-winter-is-too-cold/</link><title></title><description>Winter is too cold</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 21:22:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-06-me-the-sunset-is-be/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-06-me-the-sunset-is-be/</link><title></title><description>Me: the sunset is beautiful. Fall is amazing how it feels like the sun has been setting for 4 hours.
May: so true bestie 😌</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 22:13:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-01-worst-combo-staying/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-11-01-worst-combo-staying/</link><title></title><description>Worst combo: staying up until 1 am playing a video game (Neon White), and then forgetting to take my adhd meds before work</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 16:41:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-25-i-don-t-know-how-to/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-25-i-don-t-know-how-to/</link><title>i don't know how to be online friends with people</title><description>i have a number of friends i used to see semi-regularly (at least once a year) that was helped by us both being active on facebook. now none of us are very active on facebook and i had some kids and everything is harder to schedule.it's easy to say, "hey i know we haven't spoken in roughly 4 years but i miss you and hope you're doing okay" but how do i have it continue after we finish the pleasantries? the opening is easy, i just wrote it, but after, one on one conversation is hard to sustain without the ease of in-person dialogue.i keep up with other friends because we're in group chats, so there's less pressure to speak directly to one person, you know? i can just throw into the chat "here's a dumb meme, here's a stray thought, here's a comment about my day". but when it's one on one, it feels like the silences are longer and it's harder to maintain any sort of connection.</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 15:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-23-george-lucas-selling/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-23-george-lucas-selling/</link><title></title><description>George Lucas selling Lucasfilm to Disney ruined Star Wars.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 12:13:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-22-me-i-wish-men-had-m/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-22-me-i-wish-men-had-m/</link><title></title><description>Me: i wish men had more variety to their socially acceptable outfits.
Also me: the only thing i like to wear is black shoes, black jeans, and black metal t shirt, with optional black suede bomber jacket.</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 14:53:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-21-money-handling-when/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-21-money-handling-when/</link><title>Money Handling When Married</title><description>Before I got married, I heard lots of advice about how to handle money in marriage, such as “have separate bank accounts” and “only use one joint bank account” and “as long as bills are covered, you should buy whatever you want” and “every penny must be accounted for to make sure nothing funny is happening”.Back when we were Dual Income No Kids, I just sent her my half of the bills (as I had moved in with her and they were all in her name). It was easy and simple. Once we had our first kid and she quit her job, there was a question of how to handle spending money. I switched my direct deposit to give me an allowance (personal bills, etc) and then send the rest to her with the comment that she could spend as much as she wanted, that I both trusted her and thought she deserved to buy whatever she wanted.This seemed fine but after two years, she admitted that she didn’t feel free to do whatever, that because her money was muddled in with the bills money, it felt bad to spend it on herself (even tho she knew I was okay with it).</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 14:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-money-handling/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2023-10-21-money-handling/</link><title>Money Handling When Married</title><description>Before I got married, I heard lots of advice about how to handle money in marriage, such as “have separate bank accounts” and “only use one joint bank account” and “as long as bills are covered, you should buy whatever you want” and “every penny must be accounted for to make sure nothing funny is happening”.Back when we were Dual Income No Kids, I just sent her my half of the bills (as I had moved in with her and they were all in her name). It was easy and simple. Once we had our first kid and she quit her job, there was a question of how to handle spending money. I switched my direct deposit to give me an allowance (personal bills, etc) and then send the rest to her with the comment that she could spend as much as she wanted, that I both trusted her and thought she deserved to buy whatever she wanted.This seemed fine but after two years, she admitted that she didn’t feel free to do whatever, that because her money was muddled in with the bills money, it felt bad to spend it on herself (even tho she knew I was okay with it).</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2023 10:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-19-oh-you-ever-see-th/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-19-oh-you-ever-see-th/</link><title></title><description>OH: "you ever see the people who dress up like that" "what like animals?" "yeah they get outfits and hang out and go places and stuff. they're called Furbies and it's like a new thing"</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-19-death-s-door/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-19-death-s-door/</link><title>Death’s Door</title><description>I’ve started Death’s Door as a palate cleanser after finishing Ghost of Tsushima. I’m an hour in and most of the way through the first dungeon. This game rocks. Feels good to play, the art is pretty and reserved, the music is real nice, and I like this little universe they’ve built. I’m surprisingly intrigued by the main conflict and I can’t wait to see where it goes.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 02:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-18-saw-someone-with-a-m/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-18-saw-someone-with-a-m/</link><title></title><description>Saw someone with a mgla shirt. I like them but at least I have the decency to be ashamed of it.</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 01:29:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-18-on-the-one-hand-i-d/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-18-on-the-one-hand-i-d/</link><title></title><description>On the one hand, I don’t wanna hate on someone’s favorite thing.On the other hand, I’m watching a truly boring-ass deathcore band rn and while I already don’t like deathcore, these folks are only making me hate them and the whole genre even more.Giancarlo Esposito face: you think deathcore is not metal. I think classification arguments are dumb as shit and deathcore sucks regardless of what genre it is. We are not the same.</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-17-i-finally-have-a-pos/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-17-i-finally-have-a-pos/</link><title></title><description>i finally have a post with shares that’s doing severals and it’s pretty neat!</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 16:32:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-17-cw-palisade-29-spoi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-17-cw-palisade-29-spoi/</link><title></title><description>https://notquitereal.bandcamp.com/track/cut-their-heads-off?_layout=standard&amp;_theme=darcannot fucking believe @jdq wrote a mission impossible variation for palisade. new favorite track, new favorite sequence. goddamn, i love this show.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 14:14:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-17-i-finished-ghost-of/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-17-i-finished-ghost-of/</link><title>i finished ghost of tsushima</title><description>got the platinum trophy cuz i was roughly one hour of collecting away from it.good game, would recommend. i spent way too long on it tho. i tried to resist my base urge to do everything and accidentally did everything, so it took me 55 hours to reach credits.i chose to honor my uncle’s wishes at the end of the game. it was the sadder choice but it felt right and it nicely wrapped up that story.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:29:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-16-at-this-point-i-don/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-16-at-this-point-i-don/</link><title>at this point, i don't know that i can view selling one's company as anything other than an evil act</title><description>owning and running a company is already mired in a complex set of circumstances and power relationships that i don't have a firm grasp on, but i at least see an aspect of "thing i built alongside other people and have pride in and want to see succeed as a reflection of myself".and it's like "yes, get the bag, take the money and run" but also, fucking no way dude, have some pride and dignity. “take the money and run” only applies when no one is reliant on you. once you have staff and people relying on you, you can't just sell out without ruining lives.my brother responded to the above with:</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 23:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2023-10-16-selling-ones-company/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2023-10-16-selling-ones-company/</link><title>selling one's company is an evil act</title><description>at this point, i don't know that i can view selling one's company as anything other than an evil actowning and running a company is already mired in a complex set of circumstances and power relationships that i don't have a firm grasp on, but i at least see an aspect of "thing i built alongside other people and have pride in and want to see succeed as a reflection of myself".and it's like "yes, get the bag, take the money and run" but also, fucking no way dude, have some pride and dignity. “take the money and run” only applies when no one is reliant on you. once you have staff and people relying on you, you can't just sell out without ruining lives.</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 19:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-16-me-reading-autistic/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-16-me-reading-autistic/</link><title></title><description>me reading autistic people describing things they do that they derive from their autism: that’s so funny, i do that too</description><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 12:36:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-15-i-don-t-wanna-be-a-c/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-15-i-don-t-wanna-be-a-c/</link><title></title><description>i don’t wanna be a cop or shame my 3yo kid out of living her life, but filling her mouth with bath bubbles is disgusting</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 23:28:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-11-today-was-not-a-good/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-11-today-was-not-a-good/</link><title></title><description>today was not a good work day. spent 8 hours struggling, finished roughly 30 min of work.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 21:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-06-i-learned-a-surprisi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-06-i-learned-a-surprisi/</link><title></title><description>I learned a surprising fact about our app today and made a little slack poll to see about else knew it, and when i revealed the answer, the staff engineer on my team was like (very graciously), “you sure about that?” He didn’t have the answer for why it wasn’t true but he was steadfast that it wasn’t. Ominous lolSo I went back over every piece of information and learned that a single flag I didn’t know about before was transparently converting certain of our sql queries from eager to cursor mode, which batches the queries to limit the amount of data in memory at once.I love to be publicly wrong lmao, just love it. At least I didn’t gloat too much before getting wrecked.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:20:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-05-bought-some-more-mus/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-10-05-bought-some-more-mus/</link><title>bought some more music</title><description>https://oromet.bandcamp.com/track/familiar-spirits?_layout=standard&amp;_theme=darsome real bangers in this haul</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 01:07:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-27-you-know-i-have-a-d/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-27-you-know-i-have-a-d/</link><title></title><description>You know, I have a deep love and fond memories of Max Payne 1, but I realized that I’ve only ever played it with the kung-fu mod that added sick flips and staff fighting. I bet it’s less good without that mod.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 15:39:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-25-2fa-is-the-worst-tec/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-25-2fa-is-the-worst-tec/</link><title>2FA is the worst technological development in the history of the human race.</title><description>it's so fucking annoying. at this point, if i try to log onto a website and it asks me to give it a code, i just close the tab.</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 13:59:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-21-me-sowing-staying-u/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-21-me-sowing-staying-u/</link><title></title><description>Me sowing (staying up until 00:45 having sex): haha fuck yes!Me reaping (my kids waking me up at 6:15): well this sucks, what the fuck</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 11:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-19-if-you-re-gonna-crit/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-19-if-you-re-gonna-crit/</link><title>If you’re gonna criticize something, don’t make it look cool!</title><description>One of my favorite thrash bands is Warbringer. Their lyrics are generally anti-war but they fall into the trap of accidentally glorifying it . The same way full metal jacket is anti-war but it was used as a recruiting tool because soldiers love it.For example, the song Remain Violent is anti-cop and yet the lyrics and the t-shirt makes them look sick as shit. Put some red and black protestors in there! Don’t repeat their slogans!The constant threat of a shot to the chest
But defending yourself is resisting arrest
City streets that I called my home
Are starting to look like a combat zoneAll that's what they want for you to say
Is to remain silent
Now you have the right to remain
To remain violent</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 22:57:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-19-are-we-sure-taylor-d/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-19-are-we-sure-taylor-d/</link><title></title><description>Are we sure Taylor doesn’t say “my panties make your crown” in Karma?</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 16:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-18-rabbit-in-winnie-the/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-18-rabbit-in-winnie-the/</link><title></title><description>Rabbit in Winnie the Pooh is a woman and no amount of evidence will convince me otherwise</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 02:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-16-friends-at-the-table/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-16-friends-at-the-table/</link><title>Friends at the Table is a good show</title><description>Gonna have fun explaining this one</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 19:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-15-ceo-while-eating-lun/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-15-ceo-while-eating-lun/</link><title></title><description>CEO while eating lunch: “Hey Jane, be a chicken Dal (spicy level 2) and grab my mail.”</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 16:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-15-got-a-new-shirt/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-15-got-a-new-shirt/</link><title>got a new shirt</title><description></description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 01:07:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-14-pixar-movie-rankings/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-14-pixar-movie-rankings/</link><title>pixar movie rankings</title><description>i watched elemental last night and while i'm still coalescing my thoughts on it, i decided to rank the pixar films. feast your eyes on this and scream at me in the comments and rechostsEDIT: descending, so cars is my favecars
toy story 2
turning red
coco
ratatouille
cars 3
a bug's life
the good dinosaur
monster's inc
luca
elemental
onward
brave
incredibles 2
the incredibles
monsters university
toy story</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 15:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2023-09-14-pixar-movie-rankings/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2023-09-14-pixar-movie-rankings/</link><title>pixar movie rankings</title><description>i watched elemental last night and while i'm still coalescing my thoughts on it, i decided to rank the pixar films. feast your eyes on this and scream at me in the comments and rechostsdescending, so cars is my fave:cars 
toy story 2 
turning red 
coco 
ratatouille 
cars 3 
a bug's life 
the good dinosaur
monster's inc 
luca 
elemental 
onward 
brave 
incredibles 2 
the incredibles 
monsters university 
toy story</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 11:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-14-how-do-you-come-up-w/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-14-how-do-you-come-up-w/</link><title>how do you come up with ideas for games lol</title><description>i do a lot of hobby programming. it's my primary hobby. i spend a lot of time writing code for fun, but it's quote unquote boring stuff like tinkering with an alternative test framework or building a linter or fixing a bug in a library i use.i sometimes think "i want to make a game, i like games, why shouldn't i?" and then i'm just... empty. completely devoid of ideas or thoughts. i know it's probably something of a muscle i must flex, but i haven't flexed it yet and it's hard to start new things.i'm only thinking of this now because of the unity stuff. feels like there's excitement in the air alongside the dread, people writing tutorials and recommending things, so why not.</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 03:46:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-12-y-all-ever-think-abo/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-12-y-all-ever-think-abo/</link><title>y’all ever think about all of the super stimuli you engage with in modern life? i do.</title><description>idk why or when this happened but at some point i learned about super stimuli and became deeply unsettled by them and i’m now leery of anything that resemble one. feels too easy to fall off the cliff and lose a sense of what’s “average”.maybe i’m just particular susceptible to them. i read some erotica earlier today and it made my chest constrict in such a way that left me shaken and a little emotionally numb after. a fairly pleasant but also worrisome experience. i want to enjoy my life, i want to be present and engaged, i don’t want to be distracted by thoughts of when i can sneak away to get my next hit of erotica lol.there are many things that feel very good but they’re mostly quite hard to get. what changes when they’re suddenly abundant?</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 03:56:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-11-me-every-afternoon/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-11-me-every-afternoon/</link><title></title><description>me every afternoon: tonight I’m going to bed at 10:30me every night at 12:15 am: fuck!</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:13:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-11-jumbled-sexuality-th/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-11-jumbled-sexuality-th/</link><title>jumbled sexuality thoughts</title><description>up front: i gotta pee real bad and im falling asleep on the couch but i had this desire to write some thoughts down and i wanna get them out before starting the work week and forgetting everything until next friday so excuse me. this is gonna be rambly and all over the place.what's my sexuality? i've been thinking about it a lot recently.in short: i like women, but i think i'm "my wife"-sexual.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 03:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-11-i-should-be-hornier/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-11-i-should-be-hornier/</link><title></title><description>i should be hornier on main</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 01:46:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-04-fast-and-furious-tho/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-04-fast-and-furious-tho/</link><title>Fast and Furious thoughts</title><description>My wife and I finished Fast and Furious 6 last night. Overall, I really like the series. The action is fun, the fights aren’t gratuitous, the characters have plot armor but there’s still plenty of tension, and I’ve totally bought into the whole “family” thing. I genuinely like the characters and watch to see them happy in their lives.However, the stakes have grown such that the last couple have felt closer to Mission Impossible or a Marvel movie than F&amp;F 1. We’re well past “over the top racing sequences as finale” and I think that’s really sad.I’m gonna keep watching them and enjoying them no doubt, just a little sad we’re so far past the (somewhat) grounded stakes of the original trio of movies.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 20:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-02-if-your-programming/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-02-if-your-programming/</link><title></title><description>If your programming language doesn’t allow dashes in identifiers, you’re a coward</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2023 20:40:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-01-i-sometimes-feel-gen/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-09-01-i-sometimes-feel-gen/</link><title></title><description>i sometimes feel gender feelings but when i think about writing them down, i imagine all of the ways it might be misinterpreted and then i feel tired and don't write any of them down.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 03:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-31-got-a-new-book/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-31-got-a-new-book/</link><title>got a new book</title><description>How much of this do I have to read before I’m cool?</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 21:07:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-30-one-must-imagine-si/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-30-one-must-imagine-si/</link><title>"one must imagine sisyphus happy"</title><description>i accidentally got nerd sniped and wrote up a patch to fix this. i suspect it wouldn't be accepted for fear of breaking existing code, but maybe we could at least print some warningsi gotta find a different hobby than "write patches for clojure that will be rejected" lmao</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 14:56:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-29-my-feed-is-like-90/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-29-my-feed-is-like-90/</link><title>my feed is like 90% syril karn</title><description>i couldn't be happier</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 03:14:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-28-looking-for-a-live-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-28-looking-for-a-live-a/</link><title>looking for a live action web series</title><description>roughly 20 years ago, i watched a live action web series, a "tv show" but made by nerds and uploaded to the internet in mp4 or quicktime or whatever format we were using back then. i'm searching for it now and cannot find it (cf popular post about how google sucks now).the show was about the crackers and hackers and leakers who got early access to music and movies and released them online, while trying to dodge the feds. the format for each episode was a view of someone's desktop screen and their IRC-equivalent chat windows as they typed messages to each other. in the corner of the screen was a live feed camera of them sitting at their computer, like twitch but with the camera angle usually being from somewhere else in the room.i remember there being like 8-10 episodes and all but the final one were this way: irc chats between the person we were following for that episode and their compatriots, and a nearly static image of them sitting at their computer, fake typing. and then the final one had some handheld camera stuff, some bad acting, and a finale i don't actually remember watching.</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 02:38:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-26-i-might-have-broken/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-26-i-might-have-broken/</link><title></title><description>I might have broken my 285 day streak yesterday (which I’ll easily recover), but it did give me this amazing Saturday time.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 13:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-25-coraline/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-25-coraline/</link><title>Coraline</title><description>Rewatched Coraline on our vacation because my 3 year old imprinted on a Coraline doll at the grocery store.The movie fuckin bangs. It’s so good, really witty, beautiful and creepy and unlike Nightmare Before Christmas (which I famously dislike). I love every character, I love the “you must collect 3 items” quest line. I love that the story is about parenting and childhood and isn’t just “my grand/parents are mean so we need to resolve that to move on”. I love the little dogs in their angel wings. I love the dreamlike sequences at the end.I love it all. 10/10</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 21:11:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-24-fallen-london/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-24-fallen-london/</link><title>Fallen London</title><description>I started playing Fallen London. So far my guy is an idiot who hits things hard. I’m not sure if I like it or don’t yet, but the setting gives me Blades in the Dark vibes so I’m sticking with it for at least a little while.Anyone got tips for newcomers?</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 02:13:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-23-old-memories/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-23-old-memories/</link><title>Old memories</title><description>Just remembered without provocation that roughly 14 years ago I had reconnected with an old friend from Livejournal. She wanted to be penpals so we exchanged addresses and she sent me a long and intimate letter with drawings in the marginalia, detailing her life after moving to San Francisco.In the letter she included a story about modeling nude. My girlfriend at the time found and read the letter and was upset about that story. She didn’t explicitly say that I couldn’t write back but she made the whole situation uncomfortable enough that I never did write back. I threw the letter away shortly after.I’m sorry I ghosted you, Sarah. Hope you’re doing okay.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 22:47:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-20-finally-watched-fast/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-20-finally-watched-fast/</link><title></title><description>Finally watched Fast and Furious. Shit ruled. No wonder the F@tt crew loves it so much.</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 23:27:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-19-cw-gamergate/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-19-cw-gamergate/</link><title></title><description>I hate that gamergate someone buried itself into our understanding of games journalism and games criticism. Frequently I find ostensibly left-leaning (or explicitly leftist) groups and communities who will parrot gg talking points about game reviews or criticism without a hint of self-awareness and then react angrily when called out about it.It’s lazy and dismissive to say that a two thousand word review, published weeks after the game’s release, is merely clickbait design to get ad views. It’s the basest kind of critique, requires no defense, and allows no discussion. It is its own kind of clickbait, a jingoism for terminally online nerds to feel like they’ve seen through some veil of reality. And it comes directly from the gg playbook, a simple means of derailing conversations and sowing distrust and discord.Anyway, I’ve loved the Facebook group “I’m begging you to play another rpg” but seeing the mods delete my comments and reward this shitty behavior has really soured my feelings.</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 17:51:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-19-it-s-fucked-up-how-g/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-19-it-s-fucked-up-how-g/</link><title></title><description>it’s fucked up how good hotline bling is</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2023 15:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-17-on-a-fuckin-tear-rec/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-17-on-a-fuckin-tear-rec/</link><title>on a fuckin tear recently</title><description>when it comes to hobby programming, i don't believe in pushing myself to work on stuff i don't feel like working on. i just lean as far into my strange desire as i have energy, and go where my curiosity leads.for many years this led to heartbreak and contributed to my deep-set sense of failure, as i slowly accrued a graveyard of unfinished projects and codebases where, once i had satisfied some core question, i walked away to do something else.but also, i'm now on my third lil project in the last month, each one has been fruitful and compelling and provocative. i don't know if or when i'll finish them, and yet i feel content with them. i've released more than 10 versions of Splint this year, so what am i looking to prove? nothing.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 03:28:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-16-song-of-the-day/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-16-song-of-the-day/</link><title>song of the day</title><description>https://mutoidman.bandcamp.com/track/siphon?_layout=standard&amp;_theme=dar</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 15:44:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-15-meetings-2-30-3/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-15-meetings-2-30-3/</link><title></title><description>Meetings:Guess I’m not getting anything done today</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 17:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-10-1898-taylor-s-versi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-10-1898-taylor-s-versi/</link><title>1898 (Taylor's Version)!!!!!!!!!</title><description>https://twitter.com/tswifterastour/status/1689519372178747392She fuckin did it! I cannot believe the conspiracy Swifties were right!!!!!! Ahhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhhh</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 13:23:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-10-why-not-post-my-soun/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-10-why-not-post-my-soun/</link><title></title><description>Why not post my soundcloud songs for y’all to “enjoy”</description><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 11:20:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-09-me-at-3-pm-every-day/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-09-me-at-3-pm-every-day/</link><title></title><description>me at 3 pm every day: oh shit, i forgot to do any real work</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 19:33:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-05-wq-bram/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-05-wq-bram/</link><title>:wq Bram</title><description>Bram Moolenaar, the creator and longtime maintainer of Vim, has passed away.I want to say lots about vim but all I can think of right now is, “thanks”.</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2023 15:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-04-me-i-probably-would/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-04-me-i-probably-would/</link><title></title><description>me: i probably woulda been a pretty good queer
my (bi) wife : hm, i don’t know</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-03-it-s-really-limiting/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-08-03-it-s-really-limiting/</link><title></title><description>It’s really limiting I can’t say “balls deep in X” at work.</description><pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 03:25:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-28-i-m-in-a-fuckin-stat/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-28-i-m-in-a-fuckin-stat/</link><title></title><description>I’m in a fuckin state rnPut on Inside Out for my kids which i haven’t seen in years and don’t remember liking much and also immediately started crying. Got a lot of raw emotions lurking it turns out</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 23:11:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-27-performance-chasing/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-27-performance-chasing/</link><title>Performance Chasing</title><description>I spend a lot of time thinking about my linter’s performance, and I’ve changed some of the ways I program in Clojure to support that. But it also means that I’ve sacrificed some of the benefits of Clojure and I’m not always writing “idiomatic” Clojure.I dream of moving to a language like Rust or Zig, one that pursues pure speed and efficiency, but I know Clojure and I’m intimately familiar with it, so it would be quite a loss of effort and time to just get back to where I am currently.And for what? My linter runs fast enough! It can lint 120k lines of Clojure in 15 seconds. Is that Ruff speeds? No but it’s pretty dang good.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 21:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-26-i-ve-been-putting-of/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-26-i-ve-been-putting-of/</link><title></title><description>I’ve been putting off implementing a feature in Splint for months because I worried it would be annoying to write, but I needed it yesterday so I took a stab at it and it basically went as smoothly as I could hope.The feature? Excluding files or file globs from being checked within specific rules or globally from inside the configuration file. Java’s java.nio.file.PathMatcher makes it really simple. I was worried I would have to implement it myself.Lots of hoopla for nothing. Feels great to see it work.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 13:57:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-25-bogos-binted-was/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-25-bogos-binted-was/</link><title></title><description>"bogos binted?" was in my dream last night</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:13:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-25-splint-v1-9-0-and-v1/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-25-splint-v1-9-0-and-v1/</link><title>Splint v1.9.0 and v1.10.0</title><description>Forgot to post after releasing v1.9.0 back in May, so this is gonna be fuckin huge.In short: v1.9 added a new rule (style/prefer-clj-string) and a new cli flag (--[no-]summary). v1.10 added reading available deps.edn and project.clj files to determine the directories to check, changing the pattern DSL to use a variation of pangloss/pattern's DSL, and to add 5 new rules, 4 of which are performance rules (style/redundant-regex-constructor, performance/assoc-many, performance/avoid-satisfies, performance/get-in-literals, performance/get-keyword).The change in v1.10 means that you can run bb splint or clojure -M:splint and it'll "just work": it'll check the primary directories and the directories under and :test alias without any extra fiddling. This makes it much easier to use quickly. I've always been annoyed at clj-kondo's insistence on forcing the --lint flag for choosing files, and loved Rubocop's "just run it" mentality.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 14:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-24-cw-palisade-19-spoi/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-24-cw-palisade-19-spoi/</link><title></title><description>What a good fucking pair of episodes. Cannot believe these bastards got an Authority sweep.</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 11:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-24-forgot-that-i-can-pl/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-24-forgot-that-i-can-pl/</link><title></title><description>Forgot that I can play games on my MacBook Pro 2019. It’s been roughly 8 years since I played anything on a computer so what are good games I can play on a laptop with a touch pad?</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:49:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-20-my-wife-made-the-mis/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-20-my-wife-made-the-mis/</link><title></title><description>My wife made the mistake of asking me the dreaded question, the one I have attempted and failed to answer for many people throughout my life: “When I push a button on my keyboard, how does it show up on the screen?”We spent 2 hours trying to figure out how to make certain concepts understandable for her. Fun quotes:Me: You know how you can build a physical object that adds two numbers together?
Wife: Really? that’s fucked up, I hate that.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 18:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-18-vampire-https-ww/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-18-vampire-https-ww/</link><title></title><description>@ridiculousdino asked:Need a vibe check on the new olivia rodrigo songvampire? this song has me so excited for the album. she has leaned into early lorde (complimentary) but with lots of anger. i like this more than everything on SOUR which was fun but felt young and kind of sloppy.</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 15:59:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-15-mi-1/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-15-mi-1/</link><title>MI-1</title><description>Watched Mission Impossible 1 for the first time in probably 20 years with my wife. This movie is fucking awesome. Can’t wait to watch the rest.</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 04:59:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-14-https-nullsignal-g/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-14-https-nullsignal-g/</link><title></title><description>https://nullsignal.games/blog/mark-your-calendars-for-the-automata-initiative/FUCKYES</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 19:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-13-i-looked-at-my-tumbl/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-13-i-looked-at-my-tumbl/</link><title></title><description>i looked at my tumblr and most of it is whatever but some of it i'm surfacing stuff that i don't like anymore, that makes me feel weird to read. hard to know what to do with it. i deleted a bunch of posts but is it worth nuking the whole thing? probably. i feel much less of a tie to it than i do my livejournal for example or my facebook, but i did spend a number of years on it actively engaged with parts of a community.</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 20:18:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-12-tears-of-the-kingdom/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-12-tears-of-the-kingdom/</link><title>tears of the kingdom feelings</title><description>sometimes i feel like i play a game and i get it, i just don't enjoy it so i put it down (uncharted series). or i get to a point where the game stops being fun for a variety of reasons (elden ring). other times tho, i spend the whole time going "i don't get it, what's the point, where's the fun?"that's where tears of the kingdom was when i stopped playing it. games like that itch at my brain, cuz i want to get it! i want to be able to say, "okay, i understand what this game is going for, i understand the intended loop of fun, regardless of whether i enjoy it or not, i have some meager understanding of the authorial intent and i think i've experienced enough of that to have a (imo) legit reaction to it"all that said, i watched a fun and slightly annoying video titled "Tears of the Kingdom Wants You to Cheat" and now i feel like i should try the game again.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2023 13:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-08-i-understand-that-co/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-08-i-understand-that-co/</link><title></title><description>I understand that consistent labels and acronyms are good, but I think QuILTBAG+ is better than LGBTQAI+.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 17:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-08-how-do-you-know-if-y/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-08-how-do-you-know-if-y/</link><title></title><description>How do you know if you’re mutuals with someone?</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 11:49:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-07-ocaml-it-s-like-has/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-07-ocaml-it-s-like-has/</link><title></title><description>@prophet asked:What is your favorite programming language you don't know? :)Ocaml! It’s like Haskell’s cooler friend. :eggbug-devious:</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:33:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-06-doom-spiraling/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-06-doom-spiraling/</link><title>doom spiraling</title><description>instead of doing work, i'm chosting because i'm at a point where i don't know that i can reasonably do my job. i've been here over a year and i still can't work tickets without significant help and multiple missed deadlines. knowledge about how the business works or what it does rolls off my mind like water off a duck's back.i think i need a new job, tho the fear lurks that no matter which job i go to, i won't be able to learn it so i'm just buying myself time.the company is good, my coworkers are nice, my boss is extremely chill and friendly, they're serious about everyone taking 4+ weeks of vacation a year and give off extra days every month like they hate work. it's an ideal workplace.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 20:19:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-05-album-is-easy-lover/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-05-album-is-easy-lover/</link><title></title><description>@ridiculousdino asked:Tell me your favorite tswift song and album please and thank youAlbum is easy: Lover. It came out the year I got married and right after my wife got pregnant, so we were very much in love and feeling hopeful for the future. We listened to it non-stop during a trip to visit my extended family. Brings up a lot of good memories.</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 18:50:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-05-current-obsession/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-05-current-obsession/</link><title>current obsession</title><description>Evermore (without Bon Iver) by Taylor Swift:https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KJiFoarEJj4</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 14:44:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-02-i-can-t-wait-for-mid/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-02-i-can-t-wait-for-mid/</link><title></title><description>I can’t wait for Midnight (Taylor’s Version), I bet that one’s gonna be a banger.</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 21:52:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-02-being-the-only-perso/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-02-being-the-only-perso/</link><title>Being the only person to have read all of Worm and not a single manga ever:</title><description>People into manga seem to really like those twin monster gods, huh.</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 04:43:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-01-cw-palisade-episode/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-01-cw-palisade-episode/</link><title></title><description>New jack music: :eggbug-relieved:The situation where is deployed: :eggbug-sob:</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 23:57:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-01-joke-seed-the-seinf/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-01-joke-seed-the-seinf/</link><title></title><description>Joke seed: the Seinfeld “i think he’s converted to Judaism merely for the jokes” scene but about being queer, with a shot of Walter white saying “it’s homophobic that Starbucks stopped selling my favorite drink”</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 23:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-01-saw-taylor-swift-las/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-07-01-saw-taylor-swift-las/</link><title>Saw Taylor Swift last night</title><description>She was great, the show was great. My wife made me a “Lover” themed friendship bracelet with our wedding date (1-11) on it and I wept during the performance of the song.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 13:43:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-30-the-1-is-my-favorite/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-30-the-1-is-my-favorite/</link><title></title><description>the 1 is my favorite taylor swift song</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 17:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-30-in-increasing-order/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-30-in-increasing-order/</link><title></title><description>@wiredaemon asked:What is a type in programming languages? Hot take answers only!In increasing order of heat:</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 13:44:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-30-more-like-net-bummer/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-30-more-like-net-bummer/</link><title></title><description>@Quelklef asked:net runnberMore like net bummer, am i right? You know, cuz i haven’t had any time to work on jnet or play netrunner at all in over a year.</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 00:32:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-29-if-i-could-do-it-all/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-29-if-i-could-do-it-all/</link><title></title><description>if i could do it all over again, i wouldn’t have kids</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 23:20:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-29-maybe-3-first-one/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-29-maybe-3-first-one/</link><title></title><description>@ridiculousdino asked:Okay. Here is the situation:
You are at a beach house. How many seagulls have to appear in your living room before you start to wonder if someone is placing them there as a very weird joke?maybe 3. first one, i'm like "okay, who left the window open." second, i'm like "wtf how do they keep getting in here". once we hit three, i start looking over my shoulder and sweating nervously.</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 20:30:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-29-the-gods-of-reason-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-29-the-gods-of-reason-a/</link><title></title><description>@moonflowers asked:why do you have asks and i dontthe gods of reason and pure chance gazed on the world they had created, and seeing an opportunity, struck me through the heart with the knowledge and vast power of responding to questions presented by persons friendly and formidable.</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 20:25:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-29-got-asks-turned-em/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-29-got-asks-turned-em/</link><title>got asks, turned 'em on</title><description>i doubt anyone has asks to ask me but if you ask an ask i'll answer the ask with the answer</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 20:17:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-25-violence-as-primary/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-25-violence-as-primary/</link><title>violence as primary verb</title><description>Following up on my previous post, I think I’m over “killing” as the primary verb in games. On the one hand I’m really enjoying the flow of Ghost of Tsushima, but on the other I can’t stop thinking “the person I killed was once as cute as my son is now and systemic forces outside their control helped shape them into being violently opposed to me”.Kind of takes the fun out of it when i can’t think of my enemies as ontologically evil. I blame Death Stranding for showing me that games about human conflict that deemphasize violence can be great.</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 23:39:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-25-what-do-you-call-it/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-25-what-do-you-call-it/</link><title>What do you call it when</title><description>I’ve started to see the power and structural implications in stories, which makes it hard to enjoy certain kinds of stories (for example anything involving royalty). It’s “copaganda” but now for everything, where I feel like I’m recognizing when stories reinforce existing power structures both in real life and in the narrative fiction.Kind of wish I could stop noticing and just enjoy stories instead of being like “this sad rich kid is the savior of the masses? Sounds fake”</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 22:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-20-amgry-about-firefox/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-20-amgry-about-firefox/</link><title>amgry about firefox</title><description>idk what it is about linux and firefox dev edition, but this shit sucks ass and is deeply unstable.clicking links will randomly disable the whole tab, showing the spinning loading icon but never resolving, and trying to copy/paste the url will give me "about:newtab" unless i press control-z which magically lets me copy the url.</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 15:02:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-11-i-refuse-to-be-under/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-11-i-refuse-to-be-under/</link><title>i refuse to be understood</title><description>I should learn Haskell.HoweverTypes are the most boring and least interesting part of programming.</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 23:32:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-11-you-know-a-lot-of-p/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-11-you-know-a-lot-of-p/</link><title></title><description>You know, a lot of Pixar protagonists are real jerks. They might grow and change so that they’re somewhat lovable by the end of the movie, but that requires stomaching watching them be mean over and over. It’s an annoying feature of Pixar’s oeuvre.Some of these movies handle it better than others (Lightening McQueen is a good example of being lovable while being a jerk), but it’s still annoying.To be specific, I’m thinking of:</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2023 11:27:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-10-pride-flag/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-10-pride-flag/</link><title>pride flag </title><description>where is a good place to buy a pride flag? amazon sucks ass</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 18:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-08-went-to-a-concert-an/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-08-went-to-a-concert-an/</link><title>went to a concert and then bought some music</title><description>Saw Cave In open for Yob recently and both were amazing. Bought a sick Yob t-shirt and Cave In long sleeve. Went home and purchased all 8 Yob albums on bandcamp and the latest Cave In album.Yob got on stage and immediately started playing. After they finished their first song, Michael Scheidt said, "We have 5 more songs. About an hour and a half.". Before playing their last song, he said, "Instead of wasting everyone's time with a fake encore, we prefer to just play really long sets. Here's our last one." and then played an extra long version of Quantum Mystic.</description><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 14:14:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-03-my-kids-asks-what/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-06-03-my-kids-asks-what/</link><title></title><description>My kids asks, “what are these baby lady bugs on the rocks?” I look up “red bug concrete” and learn they’re called clover mites and that they’re entirely harmless to animals and humans, cause no structural or visible damage, and yet the internet is stuffed to the gills with instructions to eradicate them.Humans are the dumbest pieces of shit, i s2g</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 21:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-31-splint-v1-8-0/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-31-splint-v1-8-0/</link><title>splint v1.8.0</title><description>1 new rule, 2 new outputs, and one of my favorite changes yet: continue to run after a rule throws an exception.New rules</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 15:43:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-30-i-hate-when-there-s/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-30-i-hate-when-there-s/</link><title></title><description>i hate when there's some extremely minor inefficiency in a program i'm writing and everything i can think to remove it has some big cost. by minor, i mean 4ns lol. the best alternative i can get is an increase to 15ns. shameful to spend any time on this, but this is the hot path! it could be important!probably not, but it's fun to dream.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 03:36:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-26-splint-1-70/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-26-splint-1-70/</link><title>Splint 1.70</title><description>v1.7.0 adds a new rule, a new cli flag, and two new output options. Details under the fold.</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 15:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-24-newark-hegemony/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-24-newark-hegemony/</link><title></title><description>Newark Hegemony</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:36:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-23-splint-1-6-0-and-the/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-23-splint-1-6-0-and-the/</link><title>splint 1.6.0 and then of course 1.6.1 lol</title><description>Small bug fix this time:I of course fucked up the adhoc deploy script I built, so when I pushed 1.6.0, I didn't actually tag it and didn't commit any of the changes and really just messed it all up, so I cut another release immediately. I wish I could just write the code and will it onto my user's computers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 20:10:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-22-to-all-who-like-dayl/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-22-to-all-who-like-dayl/</link><title>To all who like Daylight Saving Time</title><description>Fuck you</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-21-stood-in-the-street/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-21-stood-in-the-street/</link><title></title><description>Stood in the street to block a kid from driving 55 mph down our neighborhood street. Said, “slow down please” in a stern voice as they passed too.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-15-laptop-stickers/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-15-laptop-stickers/</link><title>laptop stickers</title><description>Still working on finding ones I like.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 23:33:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-13-finished-death-stran/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-13-finished-death-stran/</link><title>Finished death stranding</title><description>Spoilers under the foldThe game could have ended much sooner i think. The ending didn’t need to be back to back gun-based boss fights (higgs’ monster, higgs, cliff, flying tar monster), and then 4 hours of cutscenes (1 of which is in-engine and unskippable), two different credit sequences, and lots of repeated dialogue from multiple perspectives.</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 13:13:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-12-splint-1-3-0-and-1-4/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-12-splint-1-3-0-and-1-4/</link><title>Splint 1.3.0 and 1.4.0 and 1.50</title><description>Gonna put the patch notes below the foldv1.3.0 is all new rules, some of which might be helpful! These are all pretty self-explanatory:</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 15:28:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-08-culs-de-sac-more-li/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-08-culs-de-sac-more-li/</link><title></title><description>culs-de-sac? more like balls-de-sac</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 19:58:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-06-got-a-tattoo-today/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-06-got-a-tattoo-today/</link><title></title><description>Got a tattoo today</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 02:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-04-getting-a-waluigi-ta/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-04-getting-a-waluigi-ta/</link><title></title><description>getting a waluigi tattoo tomorrowgonna fill my whole leg up with dumb shit. already have a kewpie bottle on there</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2023 14:35:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-03-idk-how-people-do-re/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-03-idk-how-people-do-re/</link><title></title><description>idk how people do remote work. i've been at it for 3 years and these have been the least productive, most frustrating and painful years of my software career.work on something. get frustrated. open a new browser tab. go to facebook/cohost/lobsters/etc. immediately close the tab because i should be working and it's not helpful to just mindlessly scroll to avoid doing work. look at the code again. feel frustrated. open a new browser tab. go to...repeat for 3 years.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 20:57:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-01-dasharez0ne-https/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-05-01-dasharez0ne-https/</link><title></title><description>@dasharez0ne (HTTPS://DASHARE.ZONE) nailing it yet again</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 14:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-27-can-t-see-multiple-l/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-27-can-t-see-multiple-l/</link><title></title><description>can't see multiple lines in the most recent update unless i have a lot of them. seems that the top of input box moves up instead of the bottom moving down lol</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 20:19:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-27-disney-music-thought/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-27-disney-music-thought/</link><title>disney music thoughts</title><description>my kids are growing into prime animated movie ages, so we're been listening to a lot of the disney and related animated musicals, as well as watching other animated movies too. because of who i am as a person, i spend a lot of time deeply thinking about this stuff because it's omnipresent. i could write up whole posts about them individually but i'm just gonna put down a couple thoughts to purge them.</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 14:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-27-why-the-fuck-don-t-p/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-27-why-the-fuck-don-t-p/</link><title>why the fuck don’t phones have undo</title><description>accidentally selected the wrong block of text and deleted 10 min worth of thumb typing so i gave up on the post</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 11:55:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-26-watched-one-episode/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-26-watched-one-episode/</link><title></title><description>Watched one episode of beef and turned it off. Reminded me of Burn After Reading except these aren’t awful people who I don’t care about, they’re actually decent folks in painful situations in their life. I want both of them to succeed, so there’s no joy to watch them ruin each other’s lives over N episodes. Maybe if this was a movie, I’d suffer through, but 10-12 hours of this is way too much.</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 22:57:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-24-splint-1-2-2-and-1-2/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-24-splint-1-2-2-and-1-2/</link><title>splint 1.2.2 and 1.2.3 and 1.2.4</title><description>oops, forgot to post in here about these (not that anyone on cohost uses splint :eggbug-sob:)1.2.2 big changes:</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 16:12:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-20-dear-lazyweb-is-dsa/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-20-dear-lazyweb-is-dsa/</link><title></title><description>Dear lazyweb, is DSA good or bad?</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 22:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-20-nsfw-laying-pipe-s/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-20-nsfw-laying-pipe-s/</link><title></title><description>nsfw: laying pipesfw: data pipelining</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 15:57:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-19-cw-suicide/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-19-cw-suicide/</link><title></title><description>someone i knew roughly 6 years ago passed away at her own hand. this is the third one in the last year, which doesn't even go back to my wife's mother 1.6 years ago.there are 6 million many ways to die and i know that the older i get the more people i know will die, but this is a particularly gutting form.she had a kid, 7 or 8 years old at this point.</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 19:50:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-17-dear-assc-did-you-c/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-17-dear-assc-did-you-c/</link><title></title><description>Dear ASSC, did you change the tag sorting algorithm?Used to be that if i typed in “The”, i got “The Cohost Global Feed” and” The Global Cohost Feed” at the top (because I’ve used those, i thought) followed by random others.
Now it shows only random tags.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 13:07:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-17-take-nothing-but-foo/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-17-take-nothing-but-foo/</link><title></title><description>take nothing but footprints, leave nothing but pictures</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 13:06:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-15-i-ve-always-liked-ki/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-15-i-ve-always-liked-ki/</link><title></title><description>i’ve always liked kids but raising my own kids has now made every kid i see my own kid, invisible cities style.it’s both endearing and scary. if i think about it too much (like when chosting), makes me cry.</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 13:48:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-15-card-shark/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-15-card-shark/</link><title>card shark</title><description>Started playing card shark on my switch and it’s great. The performance required has made it much more dramatic and challenging even in this first hour. Can’t wait to see where it goes next.</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 13:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-12-i-sometimes-wonder-i/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-12-i-sometimes-wonder-i/</link><title></title><description>i sometimes wonder if programming has made me worse at other tasks.like i just bought plane tickets to visit my grandma who had a stroke. i intend to visit this weekend but for some reason i bought tickets for april 29th. why didn’t i double check?part of it is of course my adhd but another part is just writing some code and seeing what happens and adjusting after, a conversational iterative approach to discovering the solution instead of planning the solution and executing on it.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 11:45:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-11-hit-da-block/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-11-hit-da-block/</link><title>HIT DA BLOCK</title><description>don’t forget that if you read an annoying comment and click through to their profile and see that every post is the same level of annoying, you can just block ‘em and never have to deal with their annoying opinions ever again</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 01:23:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-07-dear-lazyweb-how-ma/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-07-dear-lazyweb-how-ma/</link><title></title><description>Dear lazyweb, how many hours long is main feed friends at the table? My podcast app won’t tell me.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 22:34:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-07-splint-1-2-1/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-07-splint-1-2-1/</link><title>splint 1.2.1</title><description>since 1.0, i've done a fair amount of work:shit's coming along nicely and i feel good about it. still fast as hell</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 15:18:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-06-every-story-that-s-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-06-every-story-that-s-a/</link><title></title><description>Every story that’s about kids is about generational trauma send tweet</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 22:03:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-02-watched-vivo-again-w/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-02-watched-vivo-again-w/</link><title></title><description>Watched Vivo again with my family cuz I’ve been playing the music. Still amazing, has both my wife and I crying at multiple points. Death is sad, turns out, and stories centered in grief and resolution are powerful even when wrapped up in catchy songs and beautiful art.The cgi isn’t as good as a Pixar film, they’re best in class, but the commingling of 3d and 2d in the memories/imagination sequences is perfect, and I like the stylized bodies and faces.</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 15:04:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-01-it-s-888-do-you-kn/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-04-01-it-s-888-do-you-kn/</link><title></title><description>It’s @888, do you know where your eggbugs are?</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 20:19:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-29-lazyweb-anyone-reme/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-29-lazyweb-anyone-reme/</link><title></title><description>lazyweb: anyone remember how tagging on rechosts works? i wanted to rechost my bandcamp post and post the haul with tags for all of the bands but will those show up in the individual tag pages of each band? or because it's a rechost they're just for show, for me personally?</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 14:21:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-29-forgot-to-post-the-h/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-29-forgot-to-post-the-h/</link><title>forgot to post the haul</title><description></description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 14:19:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-29-company-fired-some-o/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-29-company-fired-some-o/</link><title></title><description>company fired some of my coworkers. i somehow survived; i suspect because i'm cheaper than them. doesn't feel so good.gonna get saddled with my ex-coworker's project that he's spent a month preparing for and was going to get me up to speed on next week, lol. he's written some documentation but let's be real, there's a lot of shit in his brain he didn't put to paper and now i have to start from nearly 0 without him or our project manager (also fired) and will probably be expected to meet the same deadline.in the big meeting where the ceo talked about it after it happened, he said that the company is still doing well and we have 4 years of runway and that there's no need to panic and that we're still hiring for some positions. shameless</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 13:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-29-bought-100-of-digit/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-29-bought-100-of-digit/</link><title></title><description>Bought $100 of digital albums on bandcamp today cuz I’m tired of giving money to Spotify. The mobile app is just fine but I’m okay with that to directly support artists.</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 02:11:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-28-my-problematic-fave/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-28-my-problematic-fave/</link><title></title><description>My problematic fave toxic trait is eating Lavender’s leftovers before she’s asleep so she asks to eat the rest but they’re all gone.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 23:33:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-28-death-stranding-is-g/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-28-death-stranding-is-g/</link><title></title><description>death stranding is good. dicking around on foot or on a motorcycle, carrying shit, gazing at the beautiful vistas, getting shot at, earning likes :yeah: it all feels so good.however, my favorite character is probably gonna die and that makes me real sad.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 04:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-23-adhd-vibes/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-23-adhd-vibes/</link><title>adhd vibes</title><description>sometimes it's like i'm jacked into the matrix, the work i have in front of me consumes not just my field of vision but my entire raison d'être. every part of my brain is tuned for the problem space, every breath drives me forward like ramming speed in ben-hur, the words and thoughts shift around in front of my eyes. my thoughts get so incredibly loud that i can't hear my wife from across the table.other times, my attention feels like the subject of my focus was burned with the fire that burns things out of time. in a meeting and not picking up a single word my coworker is saying. looking at code and being unable to hold the previous expressions in my head as i scan my eyes across the screen. feeling so unmoored from my body and my experiences that i can't form sentences.frankly, both are exhausting.</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 18:40:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-22-splint-reaches-1-0/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-22-splint-reaches-1-0/</link><title>splint reaches 1.0</title><description>i don't like waiting around for version 1.0. 0ver is funny but annoying. BE NOT AFRAID. so i've released splint 1.0.it has disabling rules, it doesn't choke on any code i've thrown at it so far, and the set of rules it has is pretty great. there's loads more work to be done, such as moving most of the "lint" rules to "style", which will invariably break folks config lol, but why wait?the specific updates this time are:</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 16:27:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-22-whomst-can-i-talk-to/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-22-whomst-can-i-talk-to/</link><title>whomst can i talk to?</title><description>sometimes, i have a conflict with my wife and i'm unsure if i did the "right thing", if i acted in a way that's consistent with my values and my ideal self, and if there's space between our shared expectations that i can either stand firm and say, "i acted in an acceptable manner, it's not on me to manage this" or i can bend and say, "i acted inappropriately, i'm sorry, i'll try to do better in the future."that is hard to know and i've spent a lot of time over the years thinking about it in both directions applied to many various situations.my frustration comes when i feel like i don't have a good perspective on the situation and i want feedback or outside help. this is the perfect place for a therapist, but for various reasons, i no longer have access to one. so i could reach out to a friend or family member. but who do i want to burden with whatever nonsense i'm experiencing?</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 13:28:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-22-mike-trout/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-22-mike-trout/</link><title>mike trout</title><description>until tonight, i thought mike trout was a blaseball character</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 02:44:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-17-submissive-and-tweet/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-17-submissive-and-tweet/</link><title></title><description>submissive and tweetable</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 19:54:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-17-splint-update-magic/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-17-splint-update-magic/</link><title>splint update: magic comments edition</title><description>I did it, nerds. I added support in splint v0.1.119 for magic comments aka directives aka clj-kondo style #_:splint/disable or #_{:splint/disable [lint/plus-one]}. This means that folks can now pepper their code-base with stuff that has very limited utility! I'm very excited to see this become a piece of infrastructure when it certainly should not.I'm up to 3300 lines of Clojure, which is fucking sick. This is maybe the most code I've ever written from scratch for a single project. I'd love for other people to contribute, but as of right now, only one person has tried, and they just fixed a typo in the readme.If you use Clojure, please check this out, I would love to get your feedback.</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 04:16:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-15-splint-rambling-clo/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-15-splint-rambling-clo/</link><title>Splint rambling: Clojure Parsers</title><description>I want another parser because I want access to comments. Without comments, I can't parse magic comments, meaning I can't enable or disable rules inline, only globally. That's annoying and not ideal. However, every solution I've dreamed up has some deep issue.All times below are about parsing the 8.5k lines in clojure/core.clj.</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2023 18:36:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-14-i-don-t-know-where-i/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-14-i-don-t-know-where-i/</link><title></title><description>i don't know where in the software chain the blame lays, but the floating "new chost" box on cohost lags so much that I can type an entire sentence before the characters appear in it. this wouldn't be so bad but the dedicated "new chost" page also uses javascript and is only moderately faster, lagging behind by roughly 1 word instead of entire sentences.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 13:42:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-14-net-promoter-score-i/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-14-net-promoter-score-i/</link><title></title><description>net promoter score is a bad system which is why i only give 1s</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 13:32:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-03-announcing-splint-0/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-03-03-announcing-splint-0/</link><title>Announcing splint 0.1.69</title><description>After lots of work, I have a "good enough" version of splint, my new Clojure linter, that I can now share it with y'all. It has 73 rules, extremely minimal config and cli, and runs faster than every other linter on the market while being only moderately dumber.I have lots of big plans for this bad boy but for now, suffice to say that it works and it's fast and it's pretty dang cool to make stuff.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 20:53:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-02-28-splint-update/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-02-28-splint-update/</link><title>splint update</title><description>I’ve named my new clojure linter splint, a portmanteau of spat and lint. Spat is the name of the s-expression pattern matching/regex library I wrote, the name also a portmanteau from s-expression and pattern.Why another linter? Because I am dissatisfied with the current crop of them.</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 04:10:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-02-22-v-small-rant-about-v/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-02-22-v-small-rant-about-v/</link><title></title><description>v small rant about vue js below the foldshit sucks ass. for how much i love clojure's macros, i fucking hate this kind of magic. there's so many layers of little rules and edge cases, so many ways it just sucks to use and develop under.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 19:15:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-02-22-clojure-linters/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-02-22-clojure-linters/</link><title>Clojure Linters</title><description>Clojure’s best linter, clj-kondo, is pretty dang great. It covers a lot of ground: checks syntax, provides light type checking, tracks variables and usage, an entire hook system for linting/reading custom macros statically (without code execution), etc. it’s quite extensive.However,,,</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 04:35:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-02-20-neither-grower-nor-s/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-02-20-neither-grower-nor-s/</link><title></title><description>Neither grower nor show-er but a smaller third thing</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:11:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-01-31-thoughts-on-rrr/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2023-01-31-thoughts-on-rrr/</link><title>Thoughts on RRR</title><description>I feel like RRR showcased a style of melodrama that I don't see super frequently. The term that comes to mind is "legibility", a word/concept that @austin has placed into my brain. RRR doesn't try to use lots of dialogue or subtle acting, it leans into big emotions in all directions and keeps both the content and conveyance relatively easily understood, but then treats those big emotions as real and legitimate.Mild spoilers below:</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 20:34:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-12-20-jinteki-net-v114-rel/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-12-20-jinteki-net-v114-rel/</link><title>jinteki.net v114 release notes and thoughts</title><description>In release v114, Francesco Pellegrini fixed a whole mess of bugs, added set-mark command, and added some tests to cover bug reports we couldn't reproduce. I added compiling css and cljs in Github Actions, to catch basic compiler errors.Release Notes</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 21:12:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-12-09-full-parhelion-imple/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-12-09-full-parhelion-imple/</link><title>Full Parhelion implementation on jinteki.net</title><description>I have just released Null Signal Games' newest set Parhelion on jinteki.net. (Release notes here.)My life has been a mess the last year and it pains me that I don't have the time or availability to put 20+ hours of work into jnet anymore, as it desperately needs it, so please accept my humble apologies for the long delay between releases. Congrats to the whole jnet team for their hard work and tireless efforts in implementing 120 new cards in the span of a couple weeks in preparation for this day.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 21:21:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-22-eggbug-eggbug/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-22-eggbug-eggbug/</link><title></title><description>:eggbug: 😏 :eggbug:</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 05:26:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-15-suburban-dreams/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-15-suburban-dreams/</link><title>Suburban dreams</title><description>I have an alt that I use to write about my sex life and sexuality and related phenomena. I’d love to post it here, I suspect folks would be at least mildly interested, but I’ve accidentally become a normie.I have a wife who raises our kids while I work, and two kids who run my wife and me ragged. I have a nice suburban house and a steady paycheck and all of the modern accouterment. This is an extremely comfortable and peaceful life.I lost my job at the start of 2022 and spent 1.5 months grinding to find a new job, terrified every day that I wouldn’t and we’d lose everything. That kind of situation, that kind of fear restricts what one considers reasonable risk, meaning that I won’t post about my sex life too publicly for fear of offending the wrong person in power who could ruin my shit.</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:41:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-09-i-wonder-what-it-s-l/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-09-i-wonder-what-it-s-l/</link><title></title><description>i wonder what it's like to have ample executive function. i have some store-bought, but i forget to eat it and it's just not that useful.</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 19:54:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-09-love-waking-up-to-a/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-09-love-waking-up-to-a/</link><title></title><description>love waking up to a front page full of @starwars-characters posts because my timeline is slow at USA nighttime, love me a glup shitto</description><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 15:42:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-08-i-thought-i-hated-ga/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-08-i-thought-i-hated-ga/</link><title></title><description>I thought I hated game design but I actually hate graphics programming. I just wanna take data in and change it and push it out.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 14:16:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-08-just-lost-roughly-2k/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-08-just-lost-roughly-2k/</link><title></title><description>just lost roughly 2k words on a chost cuz I misunderstood the “save draft” button :rip:</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-05-hey-staff-what-s-t/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-05-hey-staff-what-s-t/</link><title></title><description>Hey @staff, what’s the process for giving out invites?</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 19:31:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-05-firefox-for-i-os-is-i/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-11-05-firefox-for-i-os-is-i/</link><title></title><description>Firefox for iOS is incredibly fucked rn so I’m stuck using Safari. It’s not terrible but it’s different and awkward and I just don’t like it. 😤</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2022 00:36:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-10-31-staff-feature-reque/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-10-31-staff-feature-reque/</link><title></title><description>@staff feature request: if i see a self reply to a post, can the original be skipped? It’s one of my least favorite features from tumblr: seeing reply 3 with reply 2 with reply 1 to original post, then scroll down and see reply 2 with reply 1 to original post, then scroll down and see reply 1 to original post, then scroll down and see original post. Like holy shit, yes I get it, please leave me alone.</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 04:38:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-10-31-i-commented-on-someo/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-10-31-i-commented-on-someo/</link><title></title><description>I commented on someone else’s post about open source community norms and brought up Rich Hickey’s Open Source is Not About You. I said  that I admired the stance after initially thinking it rude. However,,,I can’t help but wonder what Clojure could look like if it was less preciously held by those in charge. I don’t want Rust levels of development speed, that’s too much and too fast for my taste. But it dampens my enthusiasm for the language and my faith in the team when they respond with such disinterest in things that don’t materially impact them directly.Sharp edges and places of friction are ignored or brushed away as unimportant, like stack traces or error messages in general. Bugs that have available patches can be left to bitrot, sometimes for years (concat stack overflow patch), and bugs without patches can be ignored or treated as too prevalent to fix (keyword regex, type hinting symbol vs vector in defn).</description><pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:05:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-10-30-i-listen-to-the-egg/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-10-30-i-listen-to-the-egg/</link><title></title><description>I listen to the Eggplant podcast and think “I could make a game” but then I sit down to program and I have no ideas. The primary thing I enjoy is programming, not game design, even tho I want to enjoy game design.Same with roguelikes. Every year during Roguelikedev Does the Complete Tutorial, I give it a try even tho I am very bad at roguelikes and have never beat one or even come close.All of this is to say, I’ve joined the Lisp Game Jam 2022 using Clojure and I’m probably going to make a roguelike because graphics and action are hard lol. We’ll see how it goes!</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 23:37:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-10-30-git-init-git-add/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/cohost-mirror/2022-10-30-git-init-git-add/</link><title>git init; git add .; git commit -m ‘init’</title><description>So many dead and forgotten blogging platforms in my past. The only one I’ve ever used with any consistency was LiveJournal; I think a lot of that came from it being the only blogging platform available.I’ve used Facebook as a blogging platform in the past, writing long form thoughts and ideas to my friends. That can feel better in the moment due to the laser precision audience but there’s a low ceiling of quality engagement and the closed platform means I can’t share beyond.Why a new blog?</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 12:22:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2021-10-02-from-elegance-to-speed-with-clojure/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2021-10-02-from-elegance-to-speed-with-clojure/</link><title>From Elegance to Speed, with Clojure</title><description>I recently came across a blogpost about rewriting an "elegant" function in Clojure into an optimized function in Common Lisp.In it, John Jacobsen discusses how they went from this Clojure code:</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 22:33:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2021-08-31-restarting-the-project/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2021-08-31-restarting-the-project/</link><title>Restarting the project</title><description>I started writing a little blog in the summer of 2017, when I had really hit a local maxima happiness. A year into my software career, feeling medium good about Avuity, feeling very good about May, it seemed right to talk about it, even privately. I'm very glad I wrote all those things down. It makes me quite happy to read Marriage and see the seeds of good decisions, even if the execution took a lot of work.Why start blogging again now? Because in between writing code every day, I feel like I have thoughts and reactions to things I read and try. I read all of Test-Driven Development in a single day, and like 99 Bottles of OOP before it, I walked away with my brain on fire. I've begun reading Domain-Driven Design, and I can feel it poking at my brain in the same way. I don't want to lose this feeling, nor do I want to lose the insights these books are providing.It's very easy to grind through a tough problem (personally or professionally) and then move onto the next problem without 1) reviewing what I (we, in the context of teams) learned or what challenged me, or 2) putting any effort into practicing or preparing for the future. Mindfulness when learning and practicing goes a long way towards cementing valuable lessons, much in the same way adding and reviewing flash cards might. (I've had my time with Anki, I don't think I need to do that right now.)</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 12:01:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-27-archibus-n1-tutorial/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-27-archibus-n1-tutorial/</link><title>Archibus and the SELECT N+1 Problem</title><description>This past week, I had the opportunity to contribute to an existing custom report built for a client. It loaded incredibly slowly, so in between working on the contribution I had been tasked with, I also took it upon myself to speed it up. I think it's time to share what I've learned.Caveat</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2017 12:51:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-08-blank/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-08-blank/</link><title>Blank</title><description>I'm siting here at 1215 after another long day, and I've been thinking to myself, what am I doing? I don't need to spend the money, I don't need to drink wine, I don't need any of this. On the other hand, the wine tastes amazing, the music in my headphones and the music played by the two jazz dudes in the corner are both bangin, I'm written some really good facebook posts today. I don't regret my decisions.I had dinner with dad, and he whipped out some classic Jon Bogart-isms. Stuff like, if I actually wanted to do certain things I'd just change the rest of my life to make them happen (wrt travel vs eating out all the time). What's great is, I can let that shit fall away from me easily nowadays. I hear it, I recognize the kind of effect it's had on me at various points in my life, and I let it fall to the wayside. Jonny Dee is a smart man, he's encountered a lot over his life, and I value his wit and wisdom, but like so many pseudo-negative aspects of my life, I have to be willing to say, “No, I don't need to accept this as my current truth” the way I did in high school or college or after college.I've been feeling really good recently about my place in the world, my goals and my efforts, and the work I've put into my various relationships. I don't know exactly where I'm headed, but like I said a couple posts ago, I'm at a crossroads and I'm trying so hard to navigate this one correctly.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 21:56:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-06-pain/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-08-06-pain/</link><title>Pain</title><description>I don't know what I'm here to write, I just know that I have this feeling like I should keep it up. So here I am, writing more.What's the point of writing for one's self? Reflection? I don't get my actual feelings out if I'm not conversing with someone. Julie talks about reading her journals from when she went to therapy early in her relationship with Jon and how much clarity she finds in it, how nice it is to see the clear lines of work and effort and thought that went into various decisions in her life. I don't do that. Maybe I should? I honestly don't find it compelling to write for myself. The kinds of thoughts that I write don't accurately represent me internally in a given moment. Maybe like a sign post signifying the general area it might be helpful to write the various interpretations I've created from parts of my life, and then look back on them later, saying, "Ah from this vantage point, I can see the shape of the land, the whole from all of the pieces I could barely consider when in the tasks and minutia."Compare this to when I was in high school and early college, writing on Livejournal. I experienced so many strong emotions I had trouble processing, and writing for that kind of audience helped a bit. So many of those old posts feel like I couldn't handle the changes in my life, external and internal. Not so much like that anymore.</description><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 15:11:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-07-30-marriage/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-07-30-marriage/</link><title>Marriage</title><description>I'm at this weird crossroads in my life right now, where I can push hard to get married and settle down, and I could also dive back into the "dating" life I led in the winter/spring months. After lots of hemming and hawing, I had some excellent conversations with Ally on Friday night and Saturday morning, which has led me to the conclusion that I should get married. I should ask May, in fact, to marry me.I "preposed" to May on Saturday night, after we smanged. Almost said it during, but I had the good sense to wait until we were cuddling afterwards. Honestly, I'm a fool with timing. Thankfully, The Kindest Human, May, responded very positively and generously, considering that I had informally asked her to consider marrying me. We're having a conversation tomorrow evening (2017-07-31T20:30 ish). I hope it goes well, and based on the comments we've made to each other, I suspect the smanging will eclipse the marriage talk, lol.</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 19:09:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-07-29-intro/</guid><link>https://noahtheduke.github.io/posts/2017-07-29-intro/</link><title>Intro</title><description>Starting any project is difficult, and I suspect regular blogging is not an activity I'll have much luck with, seeing as I've classically hated all forms of writing. However, along with the work in self-care and Success Oriented Mindset I've implemented over the last year, I think it's time to attempt to conquer this issue as well.Also, at this point, all I have to do is twist something into a vaguely "programmery" design, and I fall head-over-heals into it, desperate for any reason to apply my skills at programming, even when I have no idea what I'm doing.No one will read this, and I sure as fuck hope not. That's okay. We'll see how I feel about it in a week.</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 17:15:00 -0400</pubDate></item></channel></rss>